Almost there, just an easy little hop,
Kind of.
Hey, you wanted to come this time.
Just a little - higher.
Heihei? Ow!
Hear anything?
There's gotta be other
people out here, other villages.
And one day someone's gonna answer?
Never change.
Ow! Mmm...
Heihei... You sweet beautiful chicken!
What are you waiting for?
Let's go home.
♪ Fa'alogo I galuega ♪
♪ Mana'o mai (Ia) ♪
♪ Mana'o mai (Ooheke) ♪
♪ Io io, ioa (Aueke, kimua ia) ♪
♪ Te atea, te atea ♪
♪ Heke heke toku vaka (Heke) ♪
♪ Te atea, te atea (Fano) ♪
♪ Matagofie (Eh
te atea, te atea) ♪
♪ We're back ♪
♪ Sailing from the horizon ♪
♪ Back to our home, our island ♪
♪ Coming into our view
beneath the morning sky ♪
♪ We're back ♪
♪ From new shores
we've been exploring ♪
♪ Returning to tell our story ♪
♪ Connected with both
the land and sea (aue, aue) ♪
♪ Finally we're back ♪
♪ To who we're meant to be ♪
♪ Who I'm meant to be
voyaging the sea (eya) ♪
♪ We're back ♪
♪ The village is
lush and thriving  ♪
♪ Weaving new kites for flying ♪
♪ Building new
homes and families ♪
♪ Our people just
keep expanding ♪
♪ Let's build the roof higher ♪
I can't wait till I retire.
♪ The ancestors would be proud ♪
♪ What once was
lost has been found ♪
♪ Finally we're back ♪
♪ To who we're meant to be ♪
♪ Who we're meant to be ♪
Do you have to sing?
♪ Yes, we have to sing ♪
Hey, kids.
♪ Gather round if you
wanna hear about ♪
♪ the greatest
wayfinder of all time ♪
♪ A living legend, and
she's besties with a demigod ♪
Like super besties.
♪ Together they saved our land ♪
♪ and then, like,
totally set us free ♪
♪ What's next - We'll see ♪
♪ How much better could it be ♪
♪ Unless Maui was
also friends with me ♪
Yeah, right.
Look, she's coming!
♪ Welcome our brave Moana ♪
(I wonder what she brought us.)
♪ The new canoe
needs inspecting ♪
♪ There's always
something to fix on board ♪
♪ The village believes
in her (That's right) ♪
♪ The village believes ♪
I made it past the reef!
Race the Chief to shore?
Aw, Dad, it's never much of a race.
♪ The life is back in the water ♪
♪ Our people have
come out stronger ♪
♪ The voyaging past we honor ♪
♪ Thanks to our
daughter, ohh - ay ♪
♪ Sailing from the horizon ♪
♪ Can't wait to reach my island ♪
♪ The home I've been missing ♪
♪ and the life I'm
meant to lead ♪
♪ We're back ♪
♪ Moana, she points us to the ♪
♪ future of Motunui ♪
♪ Connected with
both the land and sea ♪
♪ Oh, finally we're back ♪
♪ who we're meant to be ♪
♪ Who we're meant to be ♪
♪ (Finally we're back) ♪
♪ (Who we're meant to be) ♪
New fruit. You're gonna love it.
I don't love anything.
I'm gonna eat this chicken!
New look.
Yep, even better.
- Old as Pua.
- Oh!
His name is Bua.
- Hi, kids.
- Watch it!
You too.
Moana, lay it on me.
I mean, it takes a bit to rotate the sails.
Got it.
No, no, no, no. Oh!
- Huh?
- Yikes!
It's called a hair whip.
Learned it from those guys.
So, how'd it go this time?
You found something.
It was in a clearing, which I
found a with little help from...
Hm, Heihei, but this
isn't from our village.
I don't even know what
it's made of, but it's proof.
There are other people out there.
I don't know why we haven't
found them yet, but Dad -
that island, I think that's
where they're going to be
I just have to figure out
how to find those stars.
Little sis!
Big sis!
I thought you were gone forever.
It was three days, but
I missed you every...
What did you bring me?
Bring you?
You said you'd bring me a present.
Hmm.
Well, let me see.
Whoa.
What's it do?
What's it dr-r!
Where are we going?
This is a place of our ancestors,
where I learned our people are voyagers.
Where Grandma showed me who we are.
Gramma. She said to grab
Maui by the ear and tell him,
I am a Moana of Motunui.
You'll board my boat and
restore the heart of Ta-Fiti.
Pretty good.
Yeah.
How long did it take?
Uh, a few weeks.
Weeks? That's longer than forever.
I know, but it was important.
And if I hadn't gone,
I never would have become a wayfinder.
Like our ancient chiefs,
like the last great navigator, Taotai Vasa.
Before Maui stole Ta-Fiti's
heart and we stopped voyaging,
Taotai Vasa wanted to connect our island
to all the people of the entire ocean.
Because together, what we can do,
how far we all can go, it's endless.
And now that I'm a wayfinder,
it's my job to continue what he started.
And this - this is my first clue how.
You should make Maui
go so you can stay with me.
Well, Maui's out demigodding,
but if he ever shows up,
you will grab him by
the ear and tell him that.
Woohoo.
Woo-hoo. I'm not here to cause trouble.
Just a super chiseled
demigod passing through.
Now open the portal to the
island and I'll be on my way.
And why would I risk
breaking the rules for you
when you've already caused
my boss so much trouble?
Hey, Nalo started it.
And you'll finish it?
Team up with your precious human again?
Team? You mean the girl with the canoe
and that goofy little chicken?
We weren't a team. I just
used her to get my hook.
Ow - Ow!
Nalo is a god, Maui.
If you try to reconnect
the people of the ocean,
he will destroy you.
And then he'll destroy her too.
This is between him and me.
Moana has nothing to do with it.
Only you made her a wayfinder, Maui.
So now, she has everything to do with it.
Is this it? Whoa...
I'd like a sample of that.
Moana should stop being coy.
Ooah - ooah...
(Here you are)
Well, eat up.
We don't want the pork getting cold.
Maybe not...
Moana.
Tonight isn't just a feast.
Long ago,
there was a title given to
the last great wayfinder.
With dreams as big as yours.
The sacred title...
More than a chief,
A Tautai.
Leader, connector of the entire sea.
My dear,
would you honor us tonight
by accepting this title?
Our people's first Tautai
in a thousand years.
And show us all
just how far we'll go.
Tonight, we drink from our ancestors' foam.
As Tautai Vasa once did.
To bestow this title on you.
To connect to our past.
Our present.
And the future that lies beyond.
May the ancestors continue to guide us.
Big sis.
I am honored to serve our people.
May the ancestors continue to guide us.
Tautai Vasa...
Motufetu should be under the stars.
(INDISTINCT VOICES)
Where are my people?
Tautai Moana.
This is your future if
you cannot find others.
In isolation, this is how your story ends.
I don't understand.
Returning Ta-Fiti's
heart was the beginning.
You must brave the storm.
Reconnect our people.
Find Motufetu.
I don't know how to reach it.
A fire in the sky will guide you.
Wait, I don't even know how far it is.
Farther than I was able to go.
Find Motufetu.
Reconnect us all.
Motufetu!
The island I have to find is Motufetu.
Okay. It took some searching, but...
Motufetu.
What is it?
An ancient island where the channels
of the ocean once came together,
connecting the people of the entire sea
until it was lost, cursed.
Cursed?
In a terrible storm from a
power-hungry god, Nalo.
He believed he'd be stronger by separating
the people of the ocean to weaken us
to end our story.
Our ancestors believed reaching Motufetu
would break Nalo's curse.
Restore the channels.
It's the only way to bring
our people together again.
Or our story ends.
We need to convene a council of...
Chief!
A fire in the sky.
He wants me to follow it.
To new stars?
It could take a lifetime.
Tautai Vasa didn't make it back at all.
It's a call from the ancestors, Tui.
But if we never see her again, ah...
What do you mean, never see you again?
Simea, no, I - I mean that's...
I don't want you to leave!
Mom, it's...
It's so fast. What if...
You're a Tautai now, Moana.
For some things...
We never feel ready.
♪ I know these stars
above the ocean ♪
♪ Now new skies call me by name ♪
♪ And suddenly,
nothing feels the same ♪
♪ I know the path
that must be chosen ♪
♪ But this is
bigger than before ♪
♪ Winds have changed ♪
♪ tides turn me far
away from shore ♪
♪ What waits for me ♪
♪ forever far from home ♪
♪ From everything ♪
♪ and everyone I've ever known ♪
♪ What lies beyond ♪
♪ Under skies I've never seen ♪
♪ Will I lose myself between ♪
♪ My home and what's unknown ♪
♪ If I go beyond ♪
♪ Leaving all I love behind ♪
♪ With the future of
our people still to find ♪
♪ Can I go beyond ♪
♪ There is destiny in motion ♪
♪ And it's only just begun ♪
♪ Now will this
life I've worked ♪
♪ so hard for come undone ♪
♪ They're calling me ♪
♪ I must reply ♪
♪ But if I leave ♪
♪ How could I ever say goodbye ♪
♪ What lies beyond ♪
♪ On the vast uncharted sea ♪
♪ Will I lose myself between ♪
♪ All that we know right here ♪
♪ What's out there beyond ♪
♪ Leaving all I love behind ♪
♪ With the future of
our people still to find ♪
♪ Can I go beyond ♪
♪ If I'm not here
to hold her hand ♪
♪ Will she grow to understand ♪
Grandma.
♪ I'll always be
right beside you ♪
♪ But perhaps you're
meant for more ♪
Oh, what are you so worried about?
It's not like last time.
Last time you weren't
old enough to understand.
Oh, you could lose or learn.
But here we are, together
still. Just a little different.
I can't see where your story leads.
But we never stop choosing who we are.
This is bigger than Motunui.
Bigger than us.
So I will sail to this new sky
to reconnect the people
of the entire ocean.
And then I will return home.
♪ I'll go beyond ♪
♪ And although I
don't know when ♪
♪ I will reach
these sands again ♪
♪ 'Cause I know who I am ♪
♪ I am Moana ♪
♪ Of the land and of the sea ♪
♪ And I promise that
is who I'll always be ♪
♪ I must go, I will
go, then we'll know ♪
♪ What lies beyond ♪
Moana, you need a crew.
Heihei and Pua don't count.
It's the other side of the ocean.
How could I ask them to?
Our people will rise if you let them.
Last time the chicken made it.
Well, then I'm going
to need a bigger canoe.
Oho, yes, brand new.
Sweet!
Double hull design.
My fist can do this.
Wait...
Top of the line upgrades
for the crew, right?
Loto, I'd like you on the crew.
Oh. Well, we should do better than this.
A farmer on the sea.
We're going to need more than fish.
You need irrigation.
Plant propagation.
Take even my best apprentice.
You'd starve.
Exactly.
We need a master.
Yes, you do need a...
Thanks, Kele.
You're the best!
I walked into that one.
Hey, Maui. It's, uh, been a while.
Um, I don't know where you are,
but, whoo, I could really use your help.
Maui!
Oh, Moni.
It's both of us, actually.
Maui and me.
It's part of a series.
Wow...
It's too bad Maui isn't here.
We really need someone
who knows all the old stories.
Someone who's like super strong
and has great hair and just -
I think I know someone else
kind of like that?
Huh - Yes!
I'm going with Moana on
a call from the ancestors.
Whoo!
Get ready for some
eyewitness accounts, people.
I'm coming with you.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
I promise.
What if you don't come back?
The ocean is my friend.
Our friend.
It connects us.
So, there is nowhere I could ever go
that I won't be with you.
Go.
So you can take a piece from home.
You might want to hold on.
Okay, okay, okay.
One more time.
This is not the end of our story.
This is not where our destiny is denied.
Together, we rise as one!
Together, we take our freedom!
That guy gets it.
Yep, I mean you, handsome.
Now all you gotta do is catch my hook.
Come on.
Yes, yes.
Come on, you got it.
That's what I'm talking about.
Yes, keep doing it.
That's it, higher.
We're almost there.
Just a little higher.
Don't worry.
Come on, you know
me, I'll get us out of here.
No, I don't need her to save me...
again.
Because she'll die.
Malo hates humans even
more than he hates me.
And let me tell you something.
He hates me a lot.
So the farther Curly is
from any of this, the better.
We're on our own.
Haha, yeah, I got it.
I would let you out, but
I'm really hoping to
meet your little friend.
I have plans for you both.
- Hey - hey!
- Enjoy your lunch.
Loto! What are you doing?
Making improvements.
Okay.
The canoe is perfect as it is.
Perfection's a myth.
There is only failing,
then learning, then death.
Moni, the oar?
Of course.
That's why you're the wayfinder.
No, no, no.
Ow! Guys, the entire ocean
is kind of counting on us.
We've got to rise to the moment.
Stay on course and keep
everyone on the canoe.
Wait, where's the farmer?
Ow.
When will the canoe stop moving?
Well, we're kind of on the ocean.
Oh, Moni.
Loto. Moni's the other one.
Guys, we'll never make it - Woo!
What?
If you don't embrace the ocean.
You can't embrace a liquid.
Also, I cannot swim.
- Aw!
- Now everyone looks sad.
And whoever designed
the canoe forgot a bathroom.
I am unclear as to what you are doing.
Guys, we want to reach
Motufetu, break Nalo's curse.
We gotta come together!
Find our rhythm!
I don't need anyone!
Oh, we'll see about that!
♪ Get up and get on your feet ♪
♪ It's time to live
your own story ♪
♪ Even if you disagree ♪
♪ Compliance is mandatory ♪
♪ Look around ♪
♪ What could be
better than this? ♪
Everything's better than this.
Ocean, if you'd be so kind.
♪ Come on, you
just need some sun ♪
♪ You can't stay
in here forever ♪
♪ You're gonna miss all the fun ♪
♪ Don't you know
together's better ♪
♪ Can't you see? ♪
♪ Nothing is better than this ♪
- I'm gonna be sick.
- I know what'll help that.
♪ Feel the wind as
we're riding the waves ♪
♪ The odds are we'll
end up in watery graves ♪
Observation!
♪ Yeah, we're
ebbin' and flowin' ♪
♪ There's no sign of slowin' ♪
♪ We know where we're goin' ♪
♪ So what could
be better than this ♪
♪ What could be
better than this ♪
♪ Better than this ♪
♪ What could be
better than this ♪
♪ Woah ♪
♪ We're starting
to hit a stride ♪
I'm in for a crazy ride.
♪ We'll be there in no time ♪
♪ Because we're
in this together ♪
♪ Woah, nothing
is better than this ♪
- I think I'm going insane on the sea.
- This is so great!
Just give me one grain of sand and a tree.
♪ Yeah, we're so in the moment ♪
♪ We're rockin' and rollin' ♪
♪ We're friends with the ocean ♪
♪ So nothing is
better than this ♪
- Wrong! - What?
- Well...
Let me give you a correction
even though the song is clever.
The answer to your question
"What could possibly be better"
Technically speaking, perfection's a myth.
Even though the journey's
epic, something better could exist.
But that's why I'm
always designing, aligning.
Combining ideas, and always refining.
I'm a real bright thinker
and a genius when I tinker.
With a love of problem-solving
as a model canoe sinker.
We're failing fantastically,
yes, we're a mess.
And we're messing up drastically,
falling on your face is the best.
If you do it wrong, then
you run another test.
Yes, it's really simple, actually.
The motto of Loto until
her very last breath.
There's really only failing,
then learning, then death.
♪ What could be
better than this? ♪
- What could be better than this?
- Really, truly nothing better than this.
- Come on, Kele, the ocean's our friend.
- ♪ We're starting to understand ♪
Just take me back to land!
♪ We'll get to that island ♪
♪ Even if it's taking forever ♪
♪ Woah, nothing
is better than this ♪
Everybody now!
♪ Feel the air - in our hair ♪
♪ Watch us soar - Man the oar ♪
♪ Going where no
one's gone before ♪
♪ Woah, what could
be better than this ♪
You've got it, Kele! ♪ Woah,
what could be better than ♪
♪ This ♪
Isn't that what we were
supposed to fol-low?
Ah... Yes. Nobody panic.
I'm sure this happened for a reason.
Yeah, it's probably a good thing, right?
One of you, grab the oar!
I'm trying. Something's
wrong with the canoe!
It's not the canoe.
It's the current.
What?
Hey, ocean...
it's not like I want to
give an odd impression
other than follow the comet.
So it's not like we need a new course...
Land!
Motufetu.
We found it - really quickly.
Are those people?
That's no island...
And those aren't a people - Kakamora.
Wenano!
Oh, we're cursed. About
to be skewered by coconuts.
Good, they're just ignoring us.
Okay. You guys... Down in the hold.
- Ahaha!
- She's using centrifugal force
to make her way around them - Moana!
Ha - Bu-Bye! Thanks for the ride.
Bring it on, coco... nuts.
Hey, you will release
us! Right - right... right?
Waa - What is happening?
Uh, that is... um, fan fic.
I think they know that you drew it
but they want you to
translate that picture.
Ahaha. Oh, um...
Your home island...
Is in the same sea as Motufetu.
And when Nalo divided the ocean
to weaken the people of the sea
your ancestors were
disconnected from their home.
But you thought you
finally found a way back
when you ran into this giant clam.
And now you're worried
you'll stay separated forever.
This whole time...
They've just been trying to get home.
Wait. If we help you defeat the clam,
you'll help us reach Motufetu - together.
Yoo-hoo. Could you tell me
how we're going to beat that?
When we can't even wiggle a finger?
You went from a puzzle
on to a miracle. That's cool.
Wait, wait. I know. We could
use the liquid from one giant mussel.
If we get close enough with that stuff,
shoot it in the ganglia.
It's goodbye clam, hello Motufetu.
Huh - Do you think that'll work?
Oh. You want us to do it.
It'd be easier if we're not jelly.
Ooh, don't worry. They can fix that.
How?
What is that?
Eww - Mmm!
Alright - Oh, ho ho
ho. Tastes like coconut.
Oh, I know what a coconut does.
Okay. Where do we get
some toxin for the clam?
A dream from both ends.
Come on. We gotta go.
We made a deal. We take out the clam
and then you're helping us get to Motufetu!
Uh! You are so vain.
Oh, I think it's a warrior's
salute to show us respect.
Goodbye, end quote.
How do we shoot the ganglia
if we don't know what it looks like?
I think we're going to know
what a ganglia looks like when we see it.
So, I just "Bee-Boop" and
Motufetu, here we come?
Mission accomplished.
Oh, no - Ahh!
And this is why you always
have a backup. Woo?
And a third. Ah!
Well, a fourth would be lunacy.
No - We gotta get out!
Wait. What are you do - Ahh!
Moana - Moana? ((Moana))
Concur on the echo.
Kakamora, you did this!
I may have made an assumption there.
Fascinating. It's like an acid.
Can I get a chihu?
Oh, yeah!
Ohaha - Now I just gotta get my baby.
Maui-i-i?
The tattoo of Maui.
Listen to me. I am a demigod.
- Woo? Oh, ho-ho-ha-ha.
- I want to be slapped by the tattoo.
Hey! Okay. Rule number one.
Okay.
Uh, roll me back.
I'll roll you back.
No, no, no. Not him.
This is what happens
when you meet your heroes.
Uhh! I know, right?
Ah! Okay, rule number one.
You never saw me like this.
Even though I still look very cool.
You look like a kidney stone.
And you look like someone
who would know what that is.
Now.
Well, hello, bacon.
Okay. I feel like there's
some back story that I
need to get caught up on.
Oh! Actually, you know what? Scratch that.
I don't want to get attached if you all...
You know what I mean?
Which... which... you guys won't.
You're not gonna do that.
I don't even know why I said that.
The point is, there's some
serious god stuff going down.
And I know how to handle this one.
Alright. Be back in a bit.
Until then, stay alive. Talk to no one.
And if you see a crazy bat
lady, run. She is the worst.
Stay away or you will die. Be good.
Maui, out.
- Boat snack!
- Boat snack...
Where's Moana?
Simea? Simea!
Oh, how are you here?
I'm not. You got sucked inside a giant clam
and your story will end, 'cause now
you will never help
the people of the ocean.
And the ancestors will be like
"Moana, we hate you
forever and ever and ever..."
You got this. Yeah. You got this.
You got this.
Relax. I don't bite.
Hizzer might.
It's been a while since
I've seen a wayfinder.
Love the oar.
Would you like to see me use it?
Ooh, feisty. We have that in common, Moana.
The human who's got all the gods talking.
Who are you?
Matani, guardian of
this little slice of paradise.
You live here?
Not by choice. Maui never mentioned me?
Ha! Probably too busy
playing with his tattoo.
Well, come on then.
Um, I'm not going anywhere
with you. I need to...
Get out of here, break
Nalo's curse, find Motufetu.
Here to help.
You know the way to Motufetu?
You think you can only get
somewhere if you know the way?
That's kind of what way finding is.
Ah. So much to learn.
A true wayfinder doesn't
know the path at all.
That's the whole point.
To find your way to
what's never been found.
If you want to break Nalo's curse,
you've got to stop playing it safe, sis.
Get a little lost.
Why would I listen to anything you say?
Because Nalo trapped me too.
I want you to beat Nalo.
Because then, I'll be free.
♪ I've been stuck
a thousand years ♪
♪ Just fading, wading
through the fears ♪
♪ This giant clam
gets real old, my dear ♪
♪ So come real
close, I'll let you know ♪
♪ how you can get out of here ♪
There's always another way
to get where you need to go.
You just have to think little... different.
Different, how?
Say what?
♪ Get lost, cut loose
and lose your way ♪
♪ There ain't no pleasure
in holding back, babe ♪
♪ Enjoy the thrill of
living dangerously ♪
♪ You've got a
long long way to go ♪
♪ Keep playing safe,
you'll never know ♪
♪ the rules are ours to break ♪
♪ Come on, babe.
It's time to get lost ♪
That, is terrible advice,
Then you're not listening.
♪ Take a look around ♪
♪ Not right or left
but up and down ♪
♪ 'cause on the
edge it's all about ♪
♪ living bold and free.
Expand your mind to see ♪
♪ and put your trust in me ♪
♪ Because you've got
potential to travel the distance ♪
♪ I've been existential
and lost to existence ♪
♪ And there is no map
beyond estimation ♪
♪ and no explanation
to solve this equation ♪
♪ We gotta get lost, cut
loose and lose our way ♪
♪ There ain't no fun
in holding back, babe ♪
♪ You gotta enjoy the
thrill of living dangerously ♪
♪ You've got a long long
way to go. Keep playing safe ♪
♪ You'll never know the
rules are ours to break ♪
What is this?
♪ Don't you know
how good you have it ♪
♪ You're all that's
stopping you ♪
♪ For me, I'm stuck like static ♪
♪ Can you imagine a life
this tragic in the gloom ♪
♪ You've got a
chance, so take it ♪
♪ I know you're
scared, but life's unfair ♪
♪ It's full of choices
big and small ♪
♪ Trust the fall and
you can have it all ♪
♪ Get lost, cut loose
and lose your way ♪
♪ There ain't no fun
in holding back, babe ♪
♪ Enjoy the thrill of
living dangerously ♪
♪ You've got a long long
way to go. Keep playing safe ♪
♪ you'll never know the
rules are ours to break ♪
♪ To break. The rules
are ours to break ♪
There's always another way in life.
What are you gonna do?
Get lost.
Get lost!
Oh.
There's always another way.
Portal of the gods.
It won't get you all the way to Motufetu
but it'll shorten the commute
for you and your crew.
And Mr. Coconut Oil.
Who's Mr...
Oh. Always losing my patience.
Maui!
Do not fear. You have been rescued. Woo!
Kowa-ki-na, kowa-ki-na!
Mueha, Mueha - Mui
She opened it?
This was your plan?
Keep me in a snot cave because
you wanted us to go together?
Well, I certainly did not
keep you for the conversation.
Oh, wait.
Well, shall we?
You can't leave?
Break Nalo's curse
and maybe one day
we'll see each other again.
Remember there's always another way
Even if you have to get lost to find it.
Good luck, Tautai Moana.
You got this.
Hmm. If Nalo finds out I
helped we'll die by lightning.
Maui looked good.
- Woo!
- I'm kissing the pig!
We're in a portal of the gods!
Hey!
Hey guys!
Together again!
Plus Maui?
Where's Maui?
What's up, Curly?
Maui!
You could have told me
we were doing new outfits.
I've been rocking leaves on
my cheeks for a thousand years.
Oh... I can't believe you're here!
Hey buddy, I missed ya! Yeah.
Oh! Um, sorry. That was weird.
Was that weird?
It's the greatest day of my life.
Love this guy! Not creeping me out at all.
Can I talk to you for a second?
This is Pua.
Oh! And did you meet the kakamora?
I thought he'd lose us in the clam
but he turned out to be super great
because otherwise I never
would have met Matani
Who's great by the way
And now you!
And now we're gonna bring
the whole world together...
Sorry, you go.
You're all gonna die.
(Laughs) What?
What?
Nalo didn't just hide Motofetu in a storm.
He hid it in a monster storm
in a cursed ocean you can't escape from
and then sunk it to the bottom of the sea.
Which means a human can't reach it.
So unless I break the curse
you just bought a one
way ticket to Deadsville.
Which is why I didn't want
you coming out in the first place.
Because now you're
stuck and you're gonna die.
Your crew's gonna die.
And this time so is the chicken.
But, it's great to see you.
And we're here.
Good one on me?
But this place looks perfectly nice.
And look. The constellation.
It's right there!
Guys, the ancestors wouldn't have called
if we couldn't do this.
Unless it was a butt dial.
That'll make sense in two thousand years.
Tautai Vasa said reaching Motufetu
is the only way to give
our people a future.
If he knows so much,
how come he didn't tell
you it was ♪ sunk?
Because he told me to
follow the fire in the sky.
That led me straight to you.
Which makes sense
because if Nalo thinks he's
stronger by keeping people apart,
then maybe the way to break
his curse is by coming together.
You lift the island and I step on it.
Maui and Moana! Together again.
You're so amazing!
This is gonna work.
Right, ocean? Ocean...
Moana. The ocean cannot help you here.
Grandma.
Actually, I believe that's a welcome gift
from Nalo.
Take that, sucker!
Humans, get to your positions,
work together and let's do this!
We really gotta talk about
your recruiting process.
Gramps!
Down below.
Hate these guys.
Hey, I'm an elder!
And I'm three thousand years old.
Which makes me elder-er.
Just gotta outrun them till sunrise.
Oh, then they're nocturnal.
Uh, sure. Chi-hu!
Oh, yeah!
Did he just wink at us? Woohoo!
Behind us.
If Moana can turn the tide
in this fish battle, it'll work!
Moana!
Moni!
Moana! AHH!
Moni...
We'll figure this out.
May I speak to you, Moana?
Tautai Vasa's canoe.
Uh, uh... Ah, it's a bad
time to say I told you so
so I'm not gonna do that
because that would make you feel worse.
But I believe in you.
No one else does.
There you go. Walk it off, champ.
What? I was being nice.
Ow - No purple, no, ow!
Okay, I'll talk to her.
I know, Maui. It's just
Every time I think I know
what I'm supposed to do
everything changes.
I can't... Moni almost died!
If I'm the reason our
people's story just ends...
This is serious!
Is something distracting you?
Maybe breaking the curse is like you said.
We gotta work together.
I pull it from the sea but a
human has to land on its shores.
Look, I get it.
No one likes sucking at their job.
Why are you even here?
Because. Because I've been low before.
And I couldn't see a way forward.
And then someone came along.
Someone who I underestimated.
And she lifted me up.
I haven't done anything right
since I left my island.
Hey. There is a way out.
You wanna get through it?
You just gotta chi-hu it.
You are so bad at this.
I'm the best at this.
I was a human, but now I'm a demigod.
You never know what's next.
I do. Nalo's monster storm.
Well, you wanna get through it?
Stop trying - Woo!
♪ Here's the deal. You're
down in the dumps ♪
♪ You think you're
way off your game ♪
♪ but you can turn it around ♪
♪ come on, remember your name ♪
♪ Don't waste all this energy ♪
♪ You got the remedy
and I know your legacy ♪
♪ You got greatness inside ♪
♪ And you just gotta believe ♪
♪ You think you
don't have the tricks ♪
♪ but they're right
up your sleeve ♪
♪ These waters are frightening ♪
♪ but you bring the reckoning ♪
♪ So drop all the fear
and the questioning ♪
♪ I need a - can
I get a - Chihu ♪
♪ Who are you - Who are you ♪
♪ Who are you gonna be ♪
♪ You're gonna - you're gonna ♪
♪ make some history ♪
♪ Moana - Moana ♪
♪ Go get your destiny ♪
♪ Can I get a - can I get a ♪
♪ can I get a Woohoo ♪
♪ You gotta - you wanna ♪
♪ you need to level up ♪
♪ For sure - for sure ♪
♪ Tell them to knot the knots ♪
♪ Moana - Moana ♪
♪Come get your destiny ♪
♪ Did you hear that
did you hear that ♪
♪ did you hear that Woohoo ♪
♪ You don't need that
bullying storm god ♪
♪ Is likely for real ♪
♪ Can you imagine the
legend at this point is for reals ♪
♪ You think that it's doomsday ♪
♪ For me it's a Tuesday ♪
♪ You know what, I come
to play, come to play ♪
♪ And you hit right there
'cause I'm you and I'm trapped ♪
♪ And I'm gonna impress
you and pump you up ♪
♪ They're gonna
call me a legend ♪
♪ Swallow your pride
and live with the bad ♪
♪ pick the whole lot
and call me a friend ♪
♪ But now you got me invested ♪
♪ I'm gonna use
what I call a blessing ♪
♪ Who are you? Who are you ♪
♪ Who are you gonna be ♪
♪ You're gonna, you're gonna ♪
♪ Go make some history ♪
♪ Moana - Moana,
go get your destiny ♪
♪ I want a - Can I get a Woohoo ♪
♪ It's my turn to give a
motivational speech ♪
♪ It's your job to finally ♪
♪ practice what you preach ♪
♪ Because of you,
I'm a better me ♪
♪ I didn't even think
that was a possibility ♪
♪ You got me out
of mess after mess ♪
♪ Demigod in distress ♪
♪ but now the
roles are reversed ♪
♪ You're being put
through the test ♪
♪ So we got a plan ♪
♪ for breaking the curse ♪
♪ believe in the law,
it could be worse ♪
♪ I think you're the
greatest wayfinder ♪
I've ever met.
♪ Who are you, who
are you gonna be ♪
♪ Go make some history ♪
♪ Moana - Moana,
Come get your destiny ♪
♪ Can I get a Woohoo ♪
♪ Moana - Moana ♪
♪ you've got to level up ♪
♪ For sure - for sure ♪
♪ you gotta knot the knots ♪
♪ Moana - Moana -
come get your destiny ♪
♪ Can I get a - Can
I hear it - Woohoo ♪
♪ Moana - come on
and get your destiny ♪
♪ We need a - Can
we get a Woohoo ♪
♪ Moana - Moana,
come write your destiny ♪
♪ Can I get a - wanna
hear it - Woohoo ♪
Go get 'em princess.
Still not a princess.
Well, a lot of people think you are.
Mm, I know what I've asked of you is a lot
and our canoe is in really rough shape.
But I believe that together we...
We found a way to fix it.
With a little help from the ancestors, man.
I did the decorations.
We used the chicken.
Respect.
Nalo wants to end our story.
But we're not letting that happen.
We just have to outsmart him.
Find a new trick he's never seen before.
Well, I have been working on some ideas.
Also, we do have a demigod.
Sure, he's a little scruffy,
but he turns out better than nothing.
I think you'll agree.
Okay. We sail to the heart of Nalo's storm
Once I raise the island,
you all have to get to it.
It will be harder than
anything we faced before.
So if anyone wants to...
I, uh, spent my whole life
learning our people's stories.
Because of you, I get to live one.
Alright, then.
Let's break a curse.
Yeah, been a while since I
pulled an island from the sea.
I know I have to bend at the knees.
I've got great posture.
You know what? You, armpit.
He's growing on me - like a wart.
That's beautiful.
Okay, we do this,
we make it home.
Curly.
It's a storm.
Just a really big one.
Well, now I kind of miss the lava monster.
Ah, that's a big wave.
We can go around it.
Everyone get to your positions.
Be ready to switch it up.
You, smart stuff.
You might want to check the sundial.
Why? What time is it?
- It's Maui time!
- Whoo!
Let's lift an island and show
this windbag who's boss.
Bring the thunder!
I mean it's kind of fun, right?
Yoohoo!
Hey, whoa!
Switch it up. We're going over.
Moana, I'm on it.
Help me.
Hold on.
Yeah.
Nailed it. Hahaha.
Aw, come on!
This is coming hot.
We gotta turn! Guys?
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Maui.
It's okay. I got half of 'em. Scoreboard?
Well, Nalo's a cheater
and a coward for avoiding...
Hmhm, You know.
He doesn't care about you.
Oh, he cares about me.
I'm saying -
it's humans he wants to stop - Us.
Why are you smiling?
Because we can use it.
Distract Nalo, let him come after us.
While Maui reaches the
center and lifts the island.
We switch it up.
Okay. Curly, you couldn't
outmaneuver the storm before.
How are you going to do it now?
I think I have figured it out.
I will need to chop the mast.
If you keep coming back to help us,
we'll never break Nalo's curse.
We can draw the storm, Maui.
It's the only way.
Go as fast as you can.
Uh, look, I could pull
up a million islands.
But if you're not there
to land on 'em, then...
See you out there, Maui.
See you out there, Moana.
Bacon, eggs?
Yeah...
Giant Hawk!
So serious.
See you on the island.
- Loto...
- Move!
The spinning thing is coming.
It's a rough way to prototype this.
Rutabega!
Loto, this is the best thing yet!
Well, I couldn't have done it without Maui.
Away!
He found Motufetu.
Oh, The island. We still
have to reach the island.
We still have to reach the island!
A little busy!
Here comes another wave.
We can see.
We have to drop weight.
Come on, kid.
Lift it.
No!
Maui!
Maui...
(INDISTINCT VOICES)
There's another way.
There's always another way.
There's another way to reach the island.
There's another way! Find Maui.
Moana... Moana!
Moana. Moana? You, you can't...
Please... Please...
♪ Aue, aue, le faigata ♪
♪ Ua pa'u fa'anoanoa ♪
♪ Aue, aue, fa'ataga ola ♪
♪ Lena La'u talosaga ♪
♪ You have so much power ♪
♪ Let's stand to win ♪
♪ Let's Win ♪
♪ Oh, oh, you're so beautiful ♪
♪ let's stand to win ♪
♪ (Ke Manalo) ♪
Together still. Just a little different.
♪ We'll go beyond ♪
♪ And we'll reach
it side by side ♪
♪ We are rising with the tide ♪
♪ No shore left unexplored ♪
♪ Racing towards beyond ♪
♪ Where we all begin again ♪
♪ Where our sky and
our horizon never ends ♪
♪ We can rise, we
will rise, we will rise ♪
♪ We will go beyond ♪
Hmhm. You leveled up.
Yeah, so, does this mean...
Yes. My tatoos are still cooler than yours.
Ocean, I missed you.
Come on. Come, a little bit more.
Raising an island really
works up an appetite.
Oh, you smell so good.
It's Motunui... Home.
That one's his. A nasty Kakamula
There's so much out there.
Yeah. And, who knows?
Maybe one day, we'll find...
I really wish you would stop doing that.
People?
People...
Boom. Nailed it.
Yech, this is a mess.
You're welcome. Hey. How's it goin'?
Awesome hair whip. On it.
Guys, I'm lookin' for a Simea.
Hi. Is there a Simea here?
Ahem.
- I'm Simea.
- Hm hm, you're alright.
Umm, let me just, um.
Ooh, Maui.
Ah, Moana-be's. Hold onto that.
I thought you'd be bigger.
Yeah, like a lot bigger.
Okay. Your sister sent me
with a present for you.
Straight from Motufetu.
Whoa... What's it do?
Little sis!
Big sis!
I liked what you brought me.
I may have brought a little more.
This is just the beginning.
♪ (Tulou) Aue, aue ♪
♪ We set a course to find ♪
♪ A brand-new island
everywhere we roam ♪
♪ Aue, aue ♪
♪ We keep our
island in our mind ♪
Boat snack. Boat snack upgrade.
♪ we know the way ♪
♪ Aue, aue ♪
♪ We are explorers,
reading every sign ♪
♪ We tell the
stories of our elders ♪
♪ in a never-ending chain ♪
♪ Aue, aue ♪
♪ We keep our
island in our mind ♪
♪ And when it's
time to find home ♪
♪ we know the way ♪
♪ Oh, oh. Move Forward ♪
♪ The bird that guides you ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ The world is fun ♪
♪ Nae hakialia ♪
♪ We know the way ♪
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0