[jet engines starting]
[indistinct radio chatter]
["Danger Zone" playing]
♪ Revvin' up your engine
Listen to her howlin' roar ♪
♪ Metal under tension
Beggin' you to touch and go ♪
♪ Highway to the Danger Zone ♪
♪ Ride into the Danger Zone ♪
♪ Headin' into twilight ♪
♪ Spreadin' out
Her wings tonight ♪
♪ She got you
Jumpin' off the deck ♪
♪ Shovin' into overdrive ♪
♪ Highway to the Danger Zone ♪
♪ I'll take you right
Into the Danger Zone ♪
[engine roaring]
[reporter on radio]
Today, we're looking at
some of the hottest weather...
[chattering continues on radio]
[ratchet clicking]
[grunts]
[blows]
[motorcycle engine starts]
Hey.
What is it?
What?
We've been ordered
to stand down.
They're scrapping
the program.
They say
we fell short.
The contract threshold
is Mach 10.
Mach 10 is supposed to be
in two months.
Today's test point is Mach 9.
Well, that's not
good enough.
Says who?
Admiral Cain.
[Hondo]
The Drone Ranger.
He wants our budget for
his unmanned program.
He's on his way
to kill the test
and shut us down personally.
[chuckles]
Well, he isn't here yet.
They want Mach 10,
let's give 'em Mach 10.
[monitor beeping]
[inhales]
Now remember,
the contract threshold
is Mach 10.
Not 10.1. Not 10.2.
Mach 10.
That should keep
the program alive.
I don't like
that look, Mav.
It's the only one I got.
[Maverick]
Control, this is Darkstar.
How do you read?
Darkstar, Control.
Loud and clear. How me?
Loud and clear.
Takeoff precheck's complete.
Ready for APU start.
[instruments chime]
[Hondo]
Ready left engine start.
Ready right engine start.
Thumbs for taxi.
We are ready for taxi.
Tower, this is Darkstar.
We are taxiing
with information Alpha.
[traffic controller]
Darkstar, you are clear to taxi.
Runway 21. Winds 210, 10.
Fuel temps are looking good.
[Hondo] Control concurs.
[Maverick]
Battery's holding at 95%.
Cabin pressure looks good.
[Hondo] Control concurs.
Tower, this is Darkstar.
We're ready for takeoff.
Requesting
an unrestricted climb
to 600 and above.
[traffic controller]
Darkstar, the runway
and skies are yours.
[guard]
Rear Admiral Chester Cain.
[Hondo] Maverick,
Cain just pulled up to the gate.
It's not too late to stop,
buddy.
You know what happens to you
if you go through with this.
I know what happens
to everyone else if I don't.
Darkstar is ready for takeoff.
Everyone,
go for takeoff,
starting with engine.
Engine, go.
Thermals, go.
Fuel, go.
Electric, go.
Control surfaces, go.
[Hondo] Darkstar, Control.
You're cleared for takeoff.
All right, sweetheart,
one last ride.
[engines power up]
[Hondo] Darkstar,
you are cleared above 600.
Increase to Mach 3.5.
Cleared above 600.
[door slams]
Admiral.
Uh, just in time, sir.
I'm early. So are you.
You care to explain?
Transitioning to scramjet.
[engines roaring]
[Hondo] Uh, Mav,
Admiral Cain is asking--
Ordering.
Ordering that we
bring her down.
[Maverick imitates
audio distortion]
...op... oop... alpha...
...three, oh...
...assing... ach...
ive... .4, and--
...within six...
This is where we've had
trouble with comms, sir.
It's the Earth's curvature.
It's called "Earth Bulge."
Did anyone offer you
a coffee?
Okay.
[beeping]
He's at Mach 7,
pushing 8.
Flight data?
Receiving. Data is good.
Temperature's climbing.
Response is still stable.
We're feeling good.
[beeping]
[operator] Mach 8.8.
8.9.
Mach 9.
He's the fastest man
alive.
Talk to me, Goose.
Mach 9.1.
9.2.
[jet accelerating]
Mach 9.3.
9.4.
Approaching high hypersonic.
[beeps]
Windshield hot caution.
[alarm blaring]
Surface temp rising.
Come on, sweetheart,
just a little more.
Just a little.
[beeps]
Come on!
[shouts] Come on!
[beeps]
[gasps]
Mach 10!
[all cheering]
Put that
in your Pentagon budget!
Sir.
[whispers]
Oh, don't do it.
Don't do it.
Just...
a little push.
[beeps]
Holy shit.
[alarm blaring]
[breathes heavily]
[Cain]
You got some balls,
stick jockey.
I'll give you that.
[instruments beeping]
[alarm blaring]
Oh, shit.
Maverick.
Maverick!
[explosion]
[horn honking]
[bell jingling]
[country music playing
over speakers]
[jingling continues]
[Maverick gulping water]
[whispers]
Thank you.
Where am I?
Earth.
[Cain] Maverick.
Thirty-plus years
of service.
Combat medals.
Citations.
Only man to shoot down
three enemy planes
in the last 40 years.
"Distinguished."
[clock ticking]
Yet you can't get a promotion,
you won't retire,
and despite your best efforts,
you refuse to die.
You should be at least
a two-star admiral by now,
if not a senator.
Yet here you are:
Captain.
Why is that?
It's one of
life's mysteries, sir.
This isn't a joke.
I asked you a question.
I'm where I belong, sir.
Well, the navy
doesn't see it that way.
Not anymore.
[jet passes overhead]
These planes
you've been testing,
Captain,
one day, sooner than later,
they won't need pilots at all.
Pilots that need to sleep,
eat, take a piss.
Pilots that disobey orders.
All you did
was buy some time for
those men out there.
The future is coming,
and you're not in it.
Escort this man
off the base.
Take him to his quarters.
Wait with him
while he packs his gear.
I want him on the road
to North Island
within the hour.
North Island, sir?
Call came in
with impeccable timing,
right as I was driving here
to ground your ass
once and for all.
[scoffs]
It galls me to say it, but...
for reasons known
only to the Almighty
and your guardian angel...
you've been called back
to TOPGUN.
Sir?
You are dismissed,
Captain.
The end is inevitable, Maverick.
Your kind is headed
for extinction.
Maybe so, sir.
But not today.
[person] Captain Pete
"Maverick" Mitchell.
Your reputation precedes you.
Thank you, sir.
Wasn't a compliment.
I'm Admiral Beau Simpson.
I'm the Air Boss.
I believe
you know Admiral Bates.
Warlock, sir.
Must admit,
I wasn't expecting
an invitation back.
They're called orders,
Maverick.
You two have
something in common.
Cyclone here was first
in his class back in '88.
Actually, sir,
I finished second.
Just want to manage
expectations.
[sighs]
The target...
is an unsanctioned
uranium enrichment plant
built in violation
of a multilateral NATO treaty.
The uranium produced there
represents a direct threat
to our allies in the region.
The Pentagon
has tasked us
with assembling
a strike team
and taking it out
before it becomes
fully operational.
The plant sits
in an underground bunker
at the end of this valley.
Said valley is GPS-jammed
and defended by an extensive
surface-to-air missile array
serving a limited number
of fifth-generation fighters,
which in turn are backed up
by a plentiful reserve
of surplus aircraft.
Even a few old F-14s.
Seems like
we're not the only ones
holding on to old relics.
[Warlock]
What's your read, Captain?
Well, sir, normally
this would be a cakewalk
for the F-35's stealth,
but the GPS-jamming
negates that.
And a surface-to-air threat
necessitates a low-level
laser-guided strike
tailor-made for the F-18.
I figure,
two precision bombs,
minimum.
Makes it four aircraft
flying in pairs.
That is one hell
of a steep climb
out of there,
exposing you to all
the surface-to-air missiles.
You survive that,
it's a dogfight
all the way home.
All requirements for which
you have real-world experience.
Not in the same mission,
sir.
No.
No, someone's
not coming back from this.
Can it be done or not?
How soon before the plant
becomes operational?
Three weeks. Maybe less.
Well, it's been a while
since I've flown an F-18,
and...
I'm not sure who I'd trust
to fly the other three.
But I'll find a way
to make it work.
I think you misunderstand,
Captain.
Sir?
We don't want you to fly it.
We want you to teach it.
Teach, sir?
We've recalled
12 TOPGUN graduates
from their squadrons.
We want you to narrow
that pool down to six.
They'll fly the mission.
Is there a problem, Captain?
You know there is, sir.
Yeah.
Bradley Bradshaw,
aka "Rooster."
I understand you used to fly
with his old man.
What was his call sign?
"Goose," sir.
Tragic what happened.
Captain Mitchell
was cleared
of any wrongdoing.
Goose's death
was an accident.
[Cyclone]
Is that how you see it, Captain?
Is that how Goose's son
sees it?
With all due respect, sir,
I'm not a teacher.
You were a TOPGUN
instructor before.
That was almost 30 years ago.
I lasted two months.
It's not where
I belong.
Then let me be
perfectly blunt.
You were not my first choice.
In fact, you weren't
even on the list.
You are here at the request
of Admiral Kazansky.
Now, Iceman happens to be
a man I deeply admire,
and he seems to think
that you have something left
to offer the navy.
What that is,
I can't imagine.
You don't have to
take this job.
But let me be clear:
This will be your last post,
Captain.
You fly for TOPGUN,
or you don't fly for the navy
ever again.
[people chattering]
[person] Twenty bucks
you can't get three in a row.
[cell phone vibrating]
[bartender]
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
["Let's Dance"
playing on jukebox]
Pete.
Penny?
[chuckles]
What are you doing here?
I should ask you
the same thing.
Well, that is a long story.
I doubt that.
Yeah.
Who'd you piss off
this time?
Another admiral.
Exactly.
Are you mad at me?
Oh, Pete.
I can never stay mad at you.
That's the problem.
Huh.
I got to say, North Island
is the one place
I thought for sure
I'd never run into you.
Mmm.
How long you been here?
Bought this place
about three years ago.
Three years?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Not long after you got
shipped off to the desert for
pissing off that other admiral.
That was three years ago?
You must be
in a lot of trouble.
No way you'd come
back here willingly.
Well,
you'll sort it out.
No, I think, uh...
I think this is it.
Come on, Pete.
You've been saying that
as long as I've known you.
You said it after
they busted you for taking me
on a joyride in that F-18.
Then the next thing I know,
you're off to Bosnia.
Then Iraq. Both times.
You get yourself
in trouble,
Iceman makes a call,
and you're back in the air.
Penny, this is different.
Pete, trust me,
as improbable
as it seems right now,
somehow you'll be back
in a fighter plane
with your tail on fire.
Penny...
Too late.
What?
You were about to ask me
what time I get off.
Don't give me that look.
I'm not giving you any look.
I swear.
It always ends
the same with us, Pete.
Let's not start this time.
Okay.
♪ Put on your red shoes
And dance the blues... ♪
You look good.
[bell rings]
[customers cheering]
["Bang a Gong"
playing on jukebox]
Much appreciated, pal.
What am I missing?
"Disrespect a lady, the navy,
or put your cell phone
on my bar..."
"...and you buy a round."
For everyone?
I'm afraid rules are rules.
You're lucky it's early.
[person] Oh, come on!
What do we have here?
If it ain't Phoenix!
And here I thought
we were special, Coyote.
Turns out the invite
went to anyone.
Fellas,
this here's Bagman.
Hangman.
Whatever.
You're looking at the only
naval aviator on active duty
with a confirmed
air-to-air kill.
Stop.
Mind you, the other guy
was in a museum piece
from the Korean War.
Cold War.
Different wars,
same century.
Not this one.
Who are your friends?
Payback.
Fanboy.
Hey, Coyote.
Hey.
Who's he?
Who's who?
[Coyote]
When did you get in?
Oh, I've been here
the whole time.
The man's a stealth pilot.
Literally.
Weapons systems officer,
actually.
With no sense
of humor.
What do they call you?
Bob.
No, your call sign.
Uh...
Bob.
Bob Floyd.
You're my new backseater?
From Lemoore?
Looks like it. Yeah.
♪ Bang a gong, get it on ♪
Nine-ball, Bob.
Rack 'em.
Okay. [chuckles]
[Hangman] Penny, my dear.
[Penny] Yeah.
I'll have four more
on the old-timer.
["Tramp" playing on jukebox]
[vocalist]
That's all right, Mama.
Uh, what's up?
♪ And I'm the only
Son of a gun ♪
[Phoenix] Bradshaw!
Is that you?
This is how I find out
you're stateside?
Yeah, I just thought
I'd surprise you.
Hmm.
[grunts]
I guess I surprised you back.
It's good to see you.
Good to see you too.
Here you go.
[Hangman] Thank you.
Much appreciated, Pops.
[people chattering, laughing]
["Tramp" continues playing]
How about ringing me up
before the evening rush?
["Slow Ride" playing on jukebox]
[Hangman] Bradshaw.
As I live and breathe.
[Rooster] Hangman.
You look... good.
Well, I am good, Rooster.
I'm very good.
In fact,
I am too good
to be true.
So,
anybody know what this special
detachment is all about?
No, mission's a mission.
They don't confront me.
What I want to know:
Who's gonna be team leader?
[pool balls clatter]
And which one of y'all
has what it takes
to follow me?
Hangman, the only place
you'll lead anyone
is an early grave.
Whoo!
["Slow Ride" continues playing]
Well, anyone who follows you
is just gonna run out of fuel.
But that's just you,
ain't it, Rooster?
You're snug
on that perch,
waiting for just
the right moment...
that never comes.
♪ Slow ride ♪
I love this song!
♪ Take it easy ♪
Well,
he hasn't changed.
Nope. Sure hasn't.
♪ Take it easy ♪
[Fanboy] Check it out.
More patches.
[Payback]
That's Harvard, Yale, Omaha.
Shit, that's Fritz.
What the hell
kind of mission is this?
That's not the question
we should be asking.
Everyone here
is the best there is.
Who the hell are they
gonna get to teach us?
It's been declined.
You're kidding.
[music stops]
[customers protesting]
[piano playing]
[playing jazz]
Hey, guys. Come on.
[piano playing continues]
[Maverick]
How about...
That won't cover it.
[piano playing continues]
Uh, I'll come by tomorrow
and bring you the cash.
I'm afraid
rules are rules, Pete.
[bell ringing]
[all cheering, clapping]
[all chanting]
Overboard! Overboard!
Overboard!
Really?
[chanting continues]
Overboard! Overboard!
[all cheering, clapping]
Overboard!
Great to see you, Pete!
Overboard! Overboard!
Overboard!
[all cheering]
Thanks for the beers!
Come back anytime!
[customers whooping]
[Rooster]
♪ You shake my nerves
And you rattle my brain ♪
♪ Too much love
Drives a man insane ♪
♪ You broke my will
But what a thrill ♪
[all] ♪ Goodness gracious
Great balls of fire! ♪
♪ I laughed at love
'Cause I thought it was funny ♪
♪ But you came along
And you moved me, honey ♪
♪ I changed my mind
This love is fine ♪
♪ Goodness gracious
Great balls of fire! ♪
♪ Kiss me, baby ♪
[music fades]
[both] ♪ Goodness gracious
Great balls of fire! ♪
[Maverick]
Altitude 8,000... 7,000...
Goose, I can't reach
the ejection handle.
Eject, eject, eject!
Goose! Oh, no!
God, he loved flying
with you, Maverick.
[no audio]
[all singing]
[customers chattering, singing]
[all] ♪ Come on, baby
You're driving me crazy ♪
♪ Goodness gracious
Great balls of fire! ♪
[cheering]
[person] Attention on deck!
[chairs scraping]
[Warlock] Morning.
Welcome to your special
training detachment.
Be seated.
I'm Admiral Bates,
NAWDC commander.
You're all TOPGUN graduates.
The elite.
The best of the best.
That was yesterday.
The enemy's
new fifth-generation fighter
has leveled the playing field.
Details are few,
but you can be sure
we no longer possess
the technological advantage.
Success, now more than ever,
comes down to the man or woman
in the box.
Half of you
will make the cut.
One of you will
be named mission leader.
The other half
will remain in reserve.
Your instructor
is a TOPGUN graduate
with real-world experience
in every mission aspect
you will be expected to master.
His exploits
are legendary.
And he's considered
to be one of the finest pilots
this program has ever produced.
What he has to teach you
may very well
mean the difference
between life and death.
I give you
Captain Pete Mitchell.
Call sign: "Maverick."
Good morning.
The F-18 NATOPS.
It contains everything
they want you to know
about your aircraft.
I'm assuming you know the book
inside and out.
Damn right.
Damn straight.
You got it.
So does your enemy.
And we're off.
But what the enemy
doesn't know is your limits.
I intend to find them,
test them,
push beyond.
Today we'll start with
what you only think you know.
You show me
what you're made of.
[engines powering up]
[Maverick] Rooster.
Bradley.
Lieutenant
Bradshaw!
Yes, sir.
Let's not do it
like this.
You gonna wash me out?
That'll be up to you,
not me.
Am I dismissed?
[no audible dialogue]
["Won't Get Fooled Again"
playing]
Good morning, aviators.
This is your captain speaking.
Welcome to basic
fighter maneuvers.
As briefed, today's exercise
is dogfighting.
Guns only, no missiles.
We do not go below the hard deck
of 5,000 feet.
Working as a team, you have
to shoot me down, or else.
Or else what, sir?
Or else I shoot back.
If I shoot
either one of you down,
you both lose.
This guy needs an ego check.
We'll see to that.
What say we
put some skin in the game?
What do you have in mind?
Whoever gets shot down first
has to do 200 push-ups.
Guys. That's a lot of push-ups.
They don't
call it an exercise
for nothing, sir.
You got yourself a deal,
gentlemen.
Fight's on.
Let's turn and burn.
Fanboy, you see him?
Nothing on radar up ahead.
He must be somewhere behind us.
[vocalist] Yeah!
Damn it!
What the hell?
Shit!
♪ We don't get fooled again ♪
[Maverick] Easy, Maverick.
Let's try not to get fired
on the first day.
Tally, tally, tally!
Maverick's coming in!
Break left!
Breaking left.
Payback, where's your wingman?
Rooster, where are you?
I got your back.
I'm coming. Hang in there.
Hang in there.
Hurry up, man! Hurry up!
Payback, break right.
Breaking right.
Rooster just saved
your life, fellas.
But it's gonna cost him.
Not this time, old man.
Don't let him
get to you, Maverick.
♪ Smile and grin
At the change all around
Pick up my guitar... ♪
Rooster,
you're too low! Pull up!
You're hitting the hard deck!
[automated voice]
Altitude. Altitude.
[Rooster] Oh, shit.
♪ Get on my knees and pray ♪
[Maverick] That's a kill.
Down! 109.
♪ We don't get fooled again ♪
Down! 110.
[breathing shakily]
That should be us
down there.
[Hondo] 111!
But it's not.
Down!
And now you know
a little something
about Rooster.
Whoo!
Wow.
[Fanboy] Hold that tarmac down
till we get back, brother,
all right?
Get in there, boys.
[camera shutter clicks]
[laughs]
That's a kill.
Damn!
Smoked.
Damn it.
It was all fun and games
in that selfie, wasn't it?
Down!
[Hangman] Say, Phoenix.
How's about
we tell everybody
"Bob" stands
for something?
Other than Robert, I mean.
[Phoenix]
Don't take the bait, Bob.
Want to know why
we call him Hangman?
I got it. "Baby On Board."
[chuckles]
Shit!
Greetings, aviators.
Fight's on.
[Hangman] All right, Phoenix,
let's take this guy out!
Watch your back, Phoenix.
Break right!
Breaking right.
Where's he going?
That's why we call him Hangman.
He'll always
hang you out to dry.
Leaving your wingman.
There's a strategy
I haven't seen in a while.
He called you a man, Phoenix.
You gonna take that?
So long as he doesn't
call you a man.
Talk to me, Bob.
Where's Maverick?
[Bob] Jesus, his nose
is already coming around!
Get him off me, Hangman!
[Hangman]
For all you folks at home,
this is how you bury a fossil.
All right, Hangman.
Time to teach you a lesson.
You're out, Phoenix.
Son of a bitch!
[alarm blaring]
That's it.
Let's go, Mav.
Let's see what you got.
Come get me.
Evil be gone.
Hangman's coming.
Yeah, you're good.
I'll give you that.
♪ Meet the new boss ♪
♪ Same as the old boss ♪
Shit.
Phoenix, I can't see him.
How close am I?
Phoenix?
I'm dead, dickhead.
See you in the afterlife,
Bagman.
[chuckles]
Where is he?
Where is he? [gasps]
[beeping]
[Maverick] That's a kill.
Seventy-nine. Down.
Eighty. Down.
[Maverick]
Let's go. Who's next?
I got you, Omaha.
Damn it!
Lights out, Coyote.
Copy kill.
Down. Fifty-one.
Down. Fifty-two.
So, Rooster, mind if I ask you
a personal question?
Would it matter if I did?
What's the story
with you and Maverick?
It seems like
he's got you rattled.
That's none of your business.
Now where the hell is he?
[Maverick]
Been here the whole time.
Holy shit.
[Maverick] You see me now?
Come on, let's get it over with.
Fight's on!
What is with these two?
[breathing heavily]
All right, you put us here.
How you gonna get yourself out?
You can bail out anytime.
How low you want to go, Rooster?
I can go as low as you, sir!
And that's saying something.
What's past is past.
For both of us.
You'd like to believe that,
wouldn't you?
Hard deck is 5,000 feet, fellas.
You are running out of room.
[automated voice] Altitude.
Your strategy is about
to run us into the ground.
What's your move?
[automated voice]
Altitude. Altitude.
Altitude.
Altitude. Altitude. Altitude.
[grunting]
Altitude. Altitude.
Pull up! Pull up!
You got it.
Don't think, just do.
Come on, Rooster, you got him!
Drop down and take the shot!
It's too low.
Too late. You had your chance.
That's a kill. Knock it off.
Damn it!
Same old Rooster.
Go see Hondo
about your push-ups.
All right,
that's enough.
Rooster.
That's enough, man.
[grunts]
[Phoenix] Breaking the hard
deck, insubordination. Are you
trying to get kicked out?
Don't worry about it.
Look, I'm going
on this mission.
But if you get kicked out,
you leave us flying
with Hangman.
Talk to me.
What the hell was that?
He pulled my papers.
What? Who?
Maverick.
He pulled my application
to the Naval Academy.
Set me back four years.
Why would he do that?
[jet approaching]
[Cyclone]
The hard deck is 5,000 feet
above ground level.
A parameter is set
not just for the safety
of our pilots,
but for the safety
of their aircraft.
5,000 feet is not
just a rule. It is a law,
as immutable as gravity.
The hard deck
will be much lower
for the mission, sir.
And it will not change
without my approval!
Especially not
in the middle of an exercise.
And that Cobra maneuver
of yours? That could've got
all three of you killed.
I never want to see
that shit again.
What exactly do you suppose
you were teaching, Captain?
That as good as they are,
sir, they still have
something to learn.
You are talking about
the best fighter pilots
on the planet, Captain.
And they've been told that
their entire career,
while they've
been dropping bombs
from a high altitude
with little
to no dogfighting.
The parameters of this mission
call for something they
have never encountered.
Okay, you have less
than three weeks to teach them
how to fight as a team
and how to strike
the target.
And how to come home.
And how to come home, sir.
Every mission
has its risks.
These pilots accept that.
I don't, sir.
Every morning,
from this day forward,
you will brief us on
your instructional plans
in writing.
And nothing will change
without my express approval.
Including the hard deck, sir?
Especially the hard deck,
Captain.
[Maverick] Sir.
What is this?
It's a request to lower
the hard deck, sir,
to practice
a low-level bombing run
per the mission parameters.
You could learn a thing or two
about timing, Captain.
[Hangman] Yo, Coyote.
Take a look at this.
[Coyote] The man, the legend.
There he is.
No, no, no.
Next to him.
He look familiar to you?
What have we here?
[Hangman] Bradshaw.
As I live and breathe.
[panting]
[Maverick]
Hey, Theo, you got big.
[child] Hey, Mav.
[soft rock playing over jukebox]
Amelia?
I know. I got big.
[chuckles] Yes.
Bar opens at 5:00.
No, I just came by
to pay off a debt.
[Amelia] Mom!
Hey, how's your dad?
With his wife, in Hawaii.
Mom!
Mav says he owes you money.
Oh. Don't worry
about it.
I insist.
[sighs]
Thank you, Captain.
Consider your tab closed.
Captain? Still?
A highly decorated captain.
Finish up.
We have to get the boat
to the yard.
I can't go.
What do you mean,
you can't go?
Test tomorrow.
I have to study.
They only told us today.
Well, I can't
sail her alone.
Just use the engine.
Why are we taking her
to the yard?
[both] To fix the engine.
Mm-hmm.
I can help.
[Penny] Little rougher
than I was expecting.
You don't say.
Pull on the backstay.
We'll de-power the sails.
Okay.
What does that mean?
You're supposed to be
in the navy!
I don't sail boats, Penny.
I land on them.
It's sort of like raising
the flaps on an airplane.
So how do I do that?
[chuckles]
You pull on that
green line up there.
Green line.
Yep. Pull it hard.
Yep. Crank that winch
right there,
tighten the jib.
Crank it.
You okay?
Yeah.
Good.
Now,
you ready?
For what?
The afterburner.
Now you're in the navy.
[engine turns off]
Thanks for
helping out today.
I'm not exactly sure I helped.
Hmm.
Don't give me that look.
What look?
That one.
Good night, Pete.
Night, Penny.
[exhales]
[chuckles]
[sighs]
[Amelia] Mom, is that you?
[Penny] Yeah, it's me.
I'll make you dinner.
[Amelia] Okay.
Time is your greatest enemy.
Phase one of the mission
will be a low-level ingress
attacking in two-plane teams.
You'll fly along
this narrow canyon
to your target.
Radar-guided
surface-to-air missiles
defend the area.
These SAMs, they're lethal.
But they were designed
to protect the skies above,
not the canyon below.
That's because the enemy
knows no one is insane enough
to try and fly below them.
That's exactly what
I'm gonna train you to do.
On the day, your altitude
will be 100 feet maximum.
You exceed this altitude...
[radar beeping]
...radar will spot you
and you're dead.
[beeping intensifies]
Your airspeed
will be 660 knots
minimum.
Time to target:
two and a half minutes.
That's because
fifth-generation fighters
wait at an air base nearby.
In a head-to-head
with these planes
in your F-18s, you're dead.
That's why you need to get in,
hit your target and be gone
before these planes
even have a chance
of catching you.
This makes time
your greatest adversary.
You'll fly a route
in your nav system
that simulates the canyon.
The faster you navigate
this canyon,
the harder it'll be
to stay under the radar
of these enemy SAMs.
[grunting]
The tighter the turns,
the more intensely
the force of gravity
on your body multiplies...
[grunts]
...compressing your lungs...
[exhales]
...forcing the blood
from your brain...
[grunting]
...impairing your judgment
and reaction time.
So for today's lesson,
we're gonna take it easy
on you.
Max ceiling: 300 feet.
Time to target: three minutes.
Good luck.
[breathing heavily]
[Bob] Time to target
is one minute 30.
We are two seconds behind.
Increase to 480 knots.
We got to move, Coyote.
Copy. Increasing speed.
Oh! [grunts]
Oh, shit!
[beeping]
Why are they dead?
We broke the 300-foot ceiling,
and a SAM took us out.
No. Why are they dead?
I slowed down and didn't
give her a warning.
It was my fault.
Was there a reason you didn't
communicate with your team?
I was focusing on--
One that their family
will accept at the funeral.
None, sir.
Why didn't you
anticipate the turn?
You were briefed
on the terrain.
Don't tell me.
Tell it to his family.
Hangman, ease up.
The canyon's getting tighter.
Negative, Payback.
Increase your speed.
You're going too fast, man.
No harm in being
ahead of schedule.
Damn it, slow down!
I can't stay on the course!
You're gonna hit the wall!
Watch out! Watch out!
[radar beeping]
What happened?
[Hangman]
I flew as fast as I could.
Kind of like my ass
depended on it.
And you put your team in danger,
and your wingman's dead.
They couldn't
keep up.
[Yale] Rooster,
we're 20 seconds behind
and dropping.
[Rooster]
We're fine. Speed is good.
Increase to 500 knots.
Negative, Yale.
Hold your speed.
[Yale] Rooster, we're late!
We're alive.
We'll make up time
in the straightaway.
[Yale] We are not gonna make it.
Just trust me.
Maintain your speed.
We can make it.
Why are you dead?
You're team leader up there.
Why are you,
why is your team dead?
Sir, he's the only one
who made it to the target.
A minute late. [sighs]
He gave enemy aircraft
time to shoot him down.
He is dead.
You don't know that.
You're not flying
fast enough. You don't
have a second to waste.
We made it to the target.
And superior enemy aircraft
intercepted you on your way out.
Then it's a dogfight.
Against
fifth-generation fighters.
[Rooster] Yeah.
We'd still have a chance.
[Maverick] In an F-18.
It's not the plane, sir,
it's the pilot.
Exactly!
There's more than one way
to fly this mission.
[Hangman]
You really don't get it.
On this mission,
a man flies like Maverick here,
or a man does not
come back.
No offense intended.
Yet somehow
you always manage.
Look, I don't mean to criticize.
You're conservative, that's all.
Lieutenant.
We're going into combat, son,
on a level no living pilot's
ever seen.
Not even him.
That's no time to be
thinking about the past.
What's that
supposed to mean?
Rooster.
I can't be the only one
that knows that Maverick
flew with his old man.
That's enough.
Or that Maverick was flying
when his old man--
Lieutenant, that's enough!
[all clamoring, shouting]
That's enough.
You son of a bitch!
Hey, come on!
[chuckles] I'm cool,
I'm cool. Hey, hey.
That's enough.
[Hangman] He's not cut out
for this mission.
That's enough!
You know it.
[breathing heavily]
You know I'm right.
You're all dismissed.
[cell phone vibrating]
[sighs]
[children laughing, chattering]
Maverick.
It's come back?
No one knows.
There's nothing else
they can do.
Even speaking
is painful now.
Sarah, I'm so sorry.
[Iceman coughing]
[coughs]
[coughing]
Admiral.
How's my wingman?
[typing]
Please,
don't worry about me.
What can I do for you?
[sighs]
All right.
[chuckles]
Well, Rooster's still angry
with me about what I did.
I thought eventually
he would understand why.
I hoped he'd forgive me.
[typing]
The mission is less
than three weeks away.
The kid's not ready.
[typing]
He doesn't want
what I have to give.
Ice, please,
don't ask me to send
someone else to die.
Please don't...
Don't ask me to send him.
Send me.
I don't know how.
[sighs]
I'm not a teacher, Ice.
I'm a fighter pilot.
A naval aviator.
It's not what I am.
It's who I am.
How do I teach that?
Even if I could teach it,
it's not what Rooster wants.
It's not what
the navy wants.
That's why they canned me
the last time.
The only reason I'm here
is you.
If I send him
on this mission,
he might never come home.
And if I don't send him,
he'll never forgive me.
Either way,
I could lose him forever.
[sighs]
I know.
[exhales deeply]
[grunts]
[coughs]
[hoarsely]
The navy needs Maverick.
The kid needs Maverick.
That's why
I fought for you.
you're still here.
Thank you, Ice,
for everything.
One last thing.
Who's the better pilot?
You or me?
This is a nice moment.
Let's not ruin it.
[laughing]
["I Ain't Worried" playing]
[whistling]
♪ I don't know
What you've been told ♪
♪ But time is running out
No need to take it slow ♪
♪ I'm steppin' to ya
Toe to toe ♪
[indistinct chatter, shouting]
All right, all right.
[whistle blows]
♪ Keepin' dreams alive
1999 heroes ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it
Right now ♪
♪ Swimmin' in the floods ♪
Touchdown!
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it ♪
[cheering]
[whistle blows]
Yeah!
♪ I don't know
What you've been told ♪
[whooping]
♪ But time is running out
So spend it like it's gold ♪
♪ I'm livin' like
I'm nine zeros ♪
♪ Got no regrets
Even when I'm broke ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it
Right now ♪
♪ Keepin' dreams alive
1999 heroes ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it
Right now ♪
♪ Swimming in the floods
Dancing on the path, hero ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it ♪
[booing]
[whistle blows]
[chattering continues]
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it ♪
[exclaiming, cheering]
Sir.
What is this?
This is dogfight football.
Offense and defense
at the same time.
Who's winning?
I think they stopped
keeping score a while ago.
This detachment
still has some training
to complete, Captain.
Every available
minute matters.
Yes, sir.
So why are we out here
playing games?
You said
to create a team, sir.
There's your team.
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it ♪
[chanting]
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it
Right now ♪
♪ Keepin' dreams alive
1999 heroes ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it
Right now ♪
♪ Swimming in the floods
Dancing on the path, hero ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it ♪
[no audible dialogue]
Should I go?
Before Amelia gets back?
She'll be at her
friend's house tonight.
Oh, good.
You and Amelia, you seem...
a lot closer
than when I last saw you.
Yeah. Yeah, we are.
How do you manage?
Well,
you know, she always wanted
more freedom than I thought
she was ready for.
Hmm. Where'd she
get that from, I wonder?
I guess I realized
I also had to trust her.
Let her make some
of her own mistakes
sometimes.
Not an easy choice.
Mmm.
Is that what happened
with Rooster?
I pulled his papers
from the Naval Academy.
Took years off his career.
Why?
His mother never
wanted him to fly, not after
what happened to Goose.
She made me promise
before she died, so...
Does Rooster know that?
He will always resent me
for what I did.
Why should he resent her too?
Not an easy choice.
Hmm.
I was trying to be
the father he lost.
I just--
I wish I would've
done it better.
But the truth is...
I didn't think he was ready.
Is he ready now?
[door closes downstairs]
[Amelia] Mom, I'm home!
I thought you were staying
at Karen's tonight.
[Amelia] Karen's sick.
And I've got homework to do.
[whispers] I should go.
[sighing] You should go.
Have you had dinner yet?
[Amelia] Not yet.
You wanna go out?
No, it's okay.
I'll make you something.
I'll be down in a sec!
Wait! Not that way.
What?
Look, I have
an example to set.
I can't be
bringing guys home
on a first date.
This is not our first date.
You know what I mean.
Okay.
Fine.
But this is the last time
I go out your window.
We'll see.
No. No, I mean it.
I'm never gonna
leave you again.
Oh, shut up.
Go on, get out of here.
[grunts softly]
Just don't
break her heart again.
[Warlock] Good morning.
The uranium enrichment plant
that is your target
will be operational
earlier than expected.
Raw uranium will be delivered
to the plant in ten days' time.
As a result, your mission
has been moved up one week
in order to avoid contaminating
the target valley
with radiation.
Sir, no one here
has successfully flown
a low-level course.
Nevertheless,
you've been ordered
to move on.
Captain.
[Maverick] We have one week left
to focus on phase two.
It's the most difficult stage
of the mission.
It's a pop-up strike
with a steep dive,
requiring nothing less
than two consecutive miracles.
Two pairs of F-18s will fly
in a welded wing formation.
Teamwork. Precise coordination
of these aircraft is essential
to both the mission's success
and your survival.
As you know, the plant rests
between two mountains.
On final approach,
you'll invert directly
into a steep dive.
This allows you to maintain
the lowest possible altitude
and the only possible
attack angle.
Your target is an impact point
less than three meters wide.
The two-seat aircraft
will paint the target
with a laser bull's-eye.
[beeping]
The first pair
will breach the reactor
by dropping a laser-guided bomb
on an exposed ventilation hatch.
This will create an opening
for the second pair.
That's miracle number one.
The second team
will deliver the kill shot...
[target lock beeps]
...and destroy the target.
That's miracle number two.
If either team
misses the target...
That's a miss.
[Maverick]
...the mission is a failure.
Damn it!
[Maverick] Egress
is a steep high-G climb out
to avoid hitting this mountain.
A steep climb at that speed,
you're pulling
at least eight G's.
Nine, minimum.
The stress limit
of the F-18's airframe is 7.5.
[Maverick]
That's the accepted limit.
To survive this mission,
you'll pull beyond that,
even if it means
bending your airframe.
You'll be pulling so hard,
you'll weigh close
to 2,000 pounds,
your skull
crushing your spine...
[grunting]
...your lungs imploding
like an elephant's sitting
on your chest,
fighting with everything
you have just to keep
from blacking out.
[grunting, gasping]
And this is where you'll be
at your most vulnerable.
This is Coffin Corner.
Assuming you avoid crashing
into this mountain,
you'll climb straight up
into enemy radar while losing
all of your airspeed.
Within seconds,
you'll be fired upon
by enemy SAMs.
You've all faced
sustained G's before,
but this--
this is gonna
take you and your aircraft
to the breaking point.
Sir, is this even achievable?
The answer to that question
will come down
to the pilot in the box.
[sonic boom]
Talk to me, Bob.
We are 12 seconds
late on target.
We gotta move!
Copy. Try to stay with me.
[radar beeping]
Huh? Wait, who's that?
[Maverick] Blue Team,
you've been spotted.
Shit, it's Maverick.
What the hell is he doing here?
I'm a bandit on course
to intercept. Blue Team,
what are you gonna do?
He's 20 miles left. Ten o'clock.
700 knots closure.
Your call.
What do you want to do?
Continue. We're close.
Stay on target.
He's swinging around
to the north!
Stand by for pop-up.
Be ready on that laser, Bob.
Copy. I'm on it.
Blue Team,
bandit is still closing.
Popping now.
[grunting, gasping]
[grunts]
Talk to me, Bob.
Where's Maverick?
He's five miles out.
He's coming fast.
Target's in sight.
Where's my laser, Bob?
Deadeye! Deadeye! It's no good.
Sorry, I can't get a lock.
We're out of time.
I'm dropping blind.
Damn it, missed!
[gasping]
[target lock beeps]
[Maverick] That's tone.
Maverick's got
missile lock on us.
Shit! We're dead.
Blue Team, that's a fail.
Level out, Coyote.
[echoing] Coyote? Do you copy?
[normal] Coyote, come in.
Coyote, level wings.
Oh, God. He's in G-LOC.
[echoing] Coyote? Coyote?
He's gonna burn in!
I'm going after him.
Come on. Give me tone,
give me tone, give me tone.
[target lock beeping]
Snap out of it, Coyote.
Come on! Come on!
Come on, Coyote, come on.
Come on!
Damn it! Coyote! Coyote!
[automated voice] Pull up!
[Maverick] Coyote! Coyote!
[automated voice]
Pull up! Pull up!
Coyote, you okay? You okay?
[breathes heavily]
I'm okay. I'm good.
Good. Good.
That's enough for today.
That was close.
[sighs] Too close.
Bird strike! Bird strike!
Bird strike!
[alarm blaring]
Phoenix,
left engine's on fire!
Climbing.
Throttling back.
Shutting off fuel
to left engine.
Extinguishing fire.
[alarm continues]
Right engine is out!
It's still spinning.
Trying to restart it.
[engine powers up]
Phoenix, it's on fire.
Don't start--
Throttling up.
Oh, my God.
We're on fire! We're on fire!
Damn it!
[automated voice]
Engine fire. Right.
Extinguishing right engine.
Phoenix, Bob,
punch out, punch out!
Warning lights everywhere!
Hydraulic failure!
Flight controls.
I can't control it.
[Bob] We're going down, Phoenix!
We're going in! We're going in!
You can't save it.
Eject, eject!
Eject, eject, eject!
[automated voice]
Altitude. Altitude.
They'll keep Phoenix and Bob
in the hospital overnight
for observation.
They're gonna be okay.
That's good.
I've never lost a wingman.
You're lucky.
Fly long enough, it'll happen.
There will be others.
Easy for you to say.
No wife.
No kids.
Nobody to mourn you
when you burn in.
Go home.
Just get some sleep.
Why'd you pull my papers
at the Academy?
Why did you stand in my way?
You weren't ready.
Ready for what?
Huh?
Ready to fly like you?
No.
Ready to forget the book.
Trust your instincts.
Don't think, just do.
You think up there,
you're dead. Believe me.
My dad believed in you.
I'm not gonna make
the same mistake.
[door opens]
[Warlock] Maverick.
[bugler plays "Taps"]
[officer] Ready, aim, fire.
Ready,
aim,
fire.
[gunshots]
Ready,
aim,
fire.
[gunshots]
I can only imagine
what you must be feeling
right now.
Take some time.
Whatever you need.
I appreciate that, sir,
but there is no time.
The mission--
I'll be taking over
the training from here.
Sir?
We both know you didn't
want this job, Captain.
Sir, they're not ready.
It was your job
to get them ready.
Sir, they have to believe
that this mission can be flown.
And all you've managed to do
is teach them that it can't.
Sir--
You're grounded, Captain.
Permanently.
Sir--
That is all.
I heard.
I'm sorry.
What are you gonna do?
Ice is gone.
What choice do I have?
You'll have to
find a way back
on your own.
No, Penny.
I'm out.
This is over.
Pete.
If you lost
your wingman up there,
you'd keep fighting.
You wouldn't just give up.
Those are your pilots.
If anything
happens to them,
you'll never
forgive yourself.
I don't know what to do.
But you'll find a way.
I know you will.
[Cyclone] Captain Mitchell
is no longer your instructor.
And as of today,
there are new
mission parameters.
Time to target
is now four minutes.
[beeps]
You'll be entering
the valley level
at reduced speed.
Not to exceed 420 knots.
Sir, won't we be
giving their planes
time to intercept?
Well, Lieutenant,
you have a fighting chance
against enemy aircraft.
What are the odds of surviving
a head-on collision
with a mountain?
You'll be attacking the target
from a higher altitude,
level with the north wall.
Gonna be a little harder
to keep your lase on target,
but you will avoid
the high-G climb out.
We'll be sitting ducks
for enemy missiles.
[monitor beeping]
Who the hell is that?
[Maverick]
Maverick to Range Control.
Entering Point Alpha.
Confirm green range.
[Range Control]
Uh, Maverick, Range Control,
uh, green range is confirmed.
I don't see an event scheduled
for you, sir.
[Maverick]
Well, I'm going anyway.
Nice.
Setting time to target:
Two minutes 15 seconds.
2:15? That's impossible.
Final attack point.
Maverick's inbound.
[breathing heavily]
[beeping]
[grunting]
[rapid beeping]
Popping in three, two, one.
[target lock beeps]
Bombs away.
[grunts]
[grunting, gasping]
[beeping]
Bull's-eye! Holy shit!
[cheers]
[Bob] Yes.
Damn.
[breathing heavily]
[Cyclone] You have put me
in a difficult position,
Captain.
On the one hand,
you have demonstrated that
this mission can be flown.
Perhaps the only way
it can be survived.
On the other hand,
you did it by stealing
a multimillion-dollar
military aircraft
and flying it in such a manner
that it may never
be airworthy again.
Iceman is no longer here
to protect you.
I have everything I need
to have you court-martialed
and dishonorably discharged.
So what do I do?
Risk the lives of my pilots
and perhaps the success
of this mission
or...
risk my career
by appointing you team leader?
Sir--
I think the admiral's asking
a rhetorical question, Captain.
[ringing]
[all cheering]
[no audible dialogue]
Talk to me, Goose.
[Warlock] Captain Mitchell!
You're where you belong.
Make us proud.
It has been an honor
flying with you.
Each one of you represents
the best of the best.
This is a very specific mission.
My choice
is a reflection of that
and nothing more.
Choose your two Foxtrot teams.
Payback and Fanboy.
Phoenix and Bob.
[Cyclone] And your wingman.
Rooster.
The rest of you will stand by
on the carrier
for any reserve role
that's required.
Dismissed.
Your target
is a clear and present threat.
A secret uranium
enrichment site
under rogue state control.
It's an underground bunker,
tucked between
these two mountains.
Your route of ingress
is heavily defended
by surface-to-air missiles
backed up
by fifth-generation fighters.
Once your F-18 strike team
crosses the border,
Tomahawk missiles
from the USS Leyte Gulf
will launch
a synchronized strike
on the enemy's airfield here.
This will knock out
their runway.
But you'll have to contend with
any planes already in the air.
The moment those Tomahawks hit,
the enemy will know
you're coming.
Your time to target
will be two minutes
and 30 seconds.
Any longer than that,
and you will be exposed
to any aircraft
the Tomahawks may have missed.
This is what you've all
been training for.
Come home safely.
[indistinct radio chatter]
[engines powering up]
[helicopter whirring]
You give 'em hell!
Sir.
Sir?
I...
I just want to say--
[loud radio chatter]
We'll talk
when we get back.
Hey, Bradley! Bradley!
Hey.
You got this.
[Hondo] Maverick.
Maverick?
Hey, you with me?
I don't like that look, Mav.
It's the only one I got.
Thank you.
If I don't see you again,
Hondo,
thank you.
It's been an honor, Captain.
Dagger One,
up and ready on Catapult One.
Dagger Spare standing by.
Dagger Four, up and ready.
Dagger Three, up and ready.
Dagger Two, up and ready.
[comms officer 1]
Support assets airborne.
Strike package ready.
Standing by for launch decision.
Send them.
[comms officer 1]
Dagger Two away.
Dagger Three away.
Dagger Four away.
[radar beeping]
Comanche, Dagger One.
Standby check in.
[Comanche] Comanche 11, set.
Picture clean.
Recommend Dagger continue.
Copy. Daggers descending
below radar.
[breathing rapidly]
[radar beeping, stops]
[comms officer 1]
Daggers now below radar.
Switching to E-2 picture.
Here we go.
Enemy territory up ahead.
Feet dry in 60 seconds.
Comanche, Dagger One. Picture.
Comanche. Picture clean.
Decision is yours.
Copy.
[breathing heavily]
Dagger attack.
[comms officer 2]
Tomahawks airborne.
No turning back now.
Daggers,
assume attack formation.
Daggers set.
Proceeding to target.
Two minutes and 30 seconds
in three, two, one, mark.
Two mark.
Three mark.
Four mark.
[exhales] Going in.
[engines shrieking]
First SAM site overhead.
Looks like we're clear
on radar, Mav.
Let's not take it for granted.
More SAMs! Three o'clock high!
[breathing heavily]
We got two minutes to target.
[Payback] Copy.
We're a few seconds
behind, Rooster.
We got to move.
[comms officer 2]
Thirty seconds to Tomahawk
impact on enemy airstrip.
[radar beeps]
[Comanche]
Dagger, Comanche.
We're picking up two bandits.
Single group, two contacts.
Where the hell'd
they come from?
Long-range patrol?
Comanche, what's their heading?
[Comanche]
Bull's-eye 090, 50,
tacked southwest.
They're headed away from us.
They don't know we're here.
The second those Tomahawks
hit the air base,
those bandits are gonna move
to defend the target.
We have to get there
before they do.
Increase speed.
We got you, Mav.
Don't wait for me.
[breathing heavily]
[comms officer 1]
Sir, Daggers Two and Four
are behind schedule.
Time to target, one minute 20.
[comms officer 2]
Tomahawk impact in three, two...
Impact.
Enemy runway is destroyed.
They know we're coming now.
[Comanche]
Bandits are switching course
to defend the target.
Rooster, where are you?
[Payback] Come on, Rooster.
Bandits inbound.
We got to make up time now.
Let's turn and burn.
[panting]
Heads up, Phoenix.
Whoa!
[comms officer 1]
Sir, bandits are two minutes
from target.
Daggers are one minute
Come on, Rooster.
Move it or lose it.
Guys, we're falling behind.
We really gotta move.
If we don't increase our speed
right now,
those bandits
are gonna be waiting for us
when we reach the target.
Talk to me, Dad.
Come on, kid, you can do it.
Don't think, just do.
[exhales deeply]
Jesus, Rooster, not that fast!
That's it, kid, that's it.
All right, let's go.
Damn, Rooster, take it easy.
[comms officer 1]
Sir, Dagger Two is reengaging.
All right, now hit your target
and come home.
Thirty seconds to target.
Bob, check your laser.
Air-to-ground check complete.
Laser code verified, 1688.
Laser is a go!
Watch your heads.
Holy shit! Shit!
Payback, you with me?
Right behind you.
Phoenix, stand by
for pop-up strike.
Dagger Three in position.
Popping in three, two, one.
[grunting]
[grunts]
Get me eyes
on that target, Bob.
Dagger Three.
Stand by, Mav.
Come on, Bob, come on.
Stand by.
[target lock beeps]
I've got it. Captured!
Target acquired. Bombs away.
[grunts]
[grunting]
[gasping]
We've got impact!
Check, direct hit! Direct hit!
That's miracle number one.
Dagger Two, status.
Almost there, Mav. Almost there.
Fanboy, where's my laser?
Rooster, there's something wrong
with this laser!
Shit! Deadeye, deadeye, deadeye!
Come on, guys,
we're running out of time.
Get it online!
[Fanboy] I'm trying!
Come on, Fanboy!
Nearly there! Nearly there!
[gasping]
[grunting]
Come on, Fanboy, get it online.
There's no time.
I'm dropping blind.
Rooster, I got this!
No time. Pull up.
[Payback] Wait!
[Rooster]
Bombs away! Bombs away!
[panting]
[grunting]
[comms officer 1]
Bull's-eye, bull's-eye,
bull's-eye!
[cheering]
Miracle number two.
Now they're in Coffin Corner.
We're not out of this yet.
Here it comes.
Radar warning!
Smoke in the air.
Phoenix, break right.
Emergency jettison.
Dagger Three defending.
Here comes another one!
Dagger One defending.
Rooster, status.
Oh, my God.
Smoke in the air!
Break right, Payback!
Breaking right.
[Fanboy] Oh, my God,
here they come!
SAM on your six, Rooster!
Deploying countermeasures.
Negative contact.
Dagger One defending.
Talk to me, Bob.
Break right, Phoenix!
Break right! Mav!
Nine o'clock! Nine o'clock!
Rooster, two more on your six.
Dagger Two, defending.
Payback, SAM on your nose.
Dagger Four defending.
Rooster, tally, seven o'clock!
Talk to me, Bob!
On our six!
Dagger Two defending.
Phoenix, break right!
[Phoenix] I see it!
[overlapping radio chatter]
Dagger Two defending.
Shit, I'm out of flares!
Rooster, evade, evade!
I can't shake 'em!
They're on me! They're on me!
[shouts]
[grunts]
Mav! No!
Dagger One is hit!
I repeat, Dagger One is hit!
Maverick is down.
[Rooster] Dagger One, status.
Status!
Anyone see him?
Does anyone see him?
Dagger One, come in!
I didn't see a parachute.
We have to circle back.
[Comanche]
Comanche. Bandits inbound.
Single group, hot.
Recommend Dagger flow south.
One minute to intercept.
Get 'em back
to the carrier now.
All Daggers flow to ECP.
You have bandits
headed for you.
What about Maverick?
Tell him there's nothing
he can do for Maverick,
not in a goddamn F-18.
Dagger Spare request permission
to launch and fly air cover.
Negative, Spare.
Launch search and rescue.
Negative.
Not with bandits in the air.
But, sir,
Maverick is still out there.
We are not losing
anyone else today.
Get 'em home now.
Dagger, you are not to engage.
Repeat, do not engage.
[comms officer 1]
Dagger Two, return to carrier.
Acknowledge.
Rooster,
those bandits are closing.
We can't go back.
Rooster, he's gone.
Maverick's gone.
[breathing heavily]
[muffled whirring]
[guns powering up]
Oh, no, no.
[warning alarm beeping]
[comms officer 2]
Dagger Two is hit.
[comms officer 1]
Dagger Two, come in.
Dagger Two, do you copy?
You all right?
Yeah, I'm good.
[Rooster] What the hell?
What are you doing here?
What am I doing here?
You think I took
that missile
so you could be
down here with me?
You should be back
on the carrier by now!
I saved your life!
I saved your life.
That's the whole point.
What the hell
were you even thinking?
You told me not to think!
[both panting]
Well,
it's good to see you.
It's good to see you too.
So what's the plan?
[alarm blaring]
You're not serious.
[alarm continues]
[Rooster]
You've got to be
shitting me.
An F-14?
I shot down three MiGs
in one of those.
We don't even know
if that bag of ass can fly.
Let's find out.
Mav!
Okay.
[alarm continues]
[indistinct shouting]
There's guys up there, Mav.
Yeah.
[Rooster]
There's more over there.
[Maverick] Okay.
[Maverick] Let's start running.
[Rooster] Yeah, run. Run.
Once-- Once I give you
the signal for air,
you're gonna flip this switch
until the needle gets to 120.
When the engine starts,
you got to pull out the pins
and disconnect everything.
You understand?
Yeah.
[powers up]
Yes!
Once I'm up,
stow the ladder.
Okay. Wow.
It's been a minute, huh, Mav?
[electronics beeping, whirring]
[beeping]
Oh, my God.
This thing is so old.
All right.
Canopy?
Clear.
Both runways are cratered.
How we gonna get
this museum piece
in the air?
Why are the wings
coming out, Mav?
Mav, this is a taxiway,
not a runway.
This is a very short
taxiway, Mav.
Just hang on.
Holy shit!
Come on, come on, come on.
Needle's alive. Come on.
Mav?
That's it. Come on, come on!
All right.
Mav!
Here we go.
Holy shit.
Sir, we're receiving a signal
from Rooster's ESAT.
But there seems to be
a malfunction.
Have you lost him?
No, sir.
He's supersonic.
He's airborne.
In what?
Sir.
Overwatch reports
an F-14 Tomcat is airborne
and on course for our position.
Can't be. It can't be!
Maverick.
Okay, Rooster,
get us in touch with the boat.
I'm working on it.
Radio's out. No radar.
Everything's dead back here.
What do I do?
Talk me through it.
Okay, first the radio.
Throw the, uh--
the UHF-2 circuit breaker.
Try that.
There's 300 breakers back here.
Anything more specific?
I don't know.
That was your dad's department.
I'll figure it out.
Mav, tally two, 5:00 low.
What do we do?
Okay, listen. Just be cool.
If they knew who we were,
we'd be dead already.
Well, here they come.
What's your plan?
Just put your mask on.
Remember,
we're on the same team.
Just wave and smile.
What's that signal?
What's he saying?
No idea.
I have no idea what he's saying.
[Rooster]
What about that one? Any idea?
No, never seen that one either.
Oh, shit. His wingman is moving
into weapons envelope.
All right, listen up.
When I tell you,
you grab those rings
above your head.
That's the ejection handle.
[Rooster]
Mav, can we outrun these guys?
Not their missiles and guns.
Then it's a dogfight.
An F-14 against
fifth-gen fighters?
It's not the plane,
it's the pilot.
You'd go after 'em
if I wasn't here.
But you are here.
Come on, Mav.
Don't think.
Just do.
[grunts]
Tell me when you see
smoke in the air.
[target lock beeps]
Smoke in the air!
Hang on.
Yeah, Mav! Splash one!
Splash one!
[target lock beeps]
Here comes another one.
[grunts]
Rooster, flares!
Now, now, now!
Splitting the throttles.
Coming around.
Give me tone, give me tone.
[target lock beeps]
You got him, Mav!
You got him!
Taking the shot.
What the--
Holy shit!
What the fuck was that?
Hang on. We gotta get low.
The terrain will confuse
his targeting system.
Here he comes!
[beeping]
[grunts]
Talk to me, Rooster.
Where is he?
[Rooster] He's still on us!
We took a hit! We took a hit!
Damn it!
Come on, Mav.
Do some of that pilot shit.
Brace yourself.
[grunts]
[groans]
Holy shit.
[target lock beeping]
I got tone. Taking the shot.
Damn it!
Out of missiles.
Switching to guns.
Come on, Mav, come on.
You got him, Mav!
It's not over yet.
One last chance.
You can do this.
[Maverick] Come on, Maverick.
[alarm blaring]
Yes! Splash two!
[breathes heavily]
[beeping]
Mav, I got the radio on.
Outstanding.
Get us in touch
with the boat.
Copy that.
[alarm blaring]
Oh, my God.
Where the hell is this guy?
He's on our nose.
[clicking]
Damn it, we're out of ammo.
Smoke in the air!
Rooster, flares!
That was close.
We're out of flares, Mav.
Shit, he's already on us.
[groans] This is not good.
[grunts, panting]
We took another hit!
No, no, no, no, no!
We can't take much more of this.
We can't outrun this guy.
We got to eject.
What?
We need altitude.
Pull the ejection handles
the second I tell you.
Mav, wait!
Rooster,
there's no other way.
Eject, eject, eject!
[grunting]
Rooster, pull the handle!
Eject!
It's not working!
[beeping]
Mav! [breathing heavily]
[whispers] I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Goose.
[target lock beeps]
Good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen.
This is your savior speaking.
Please fasten your seat belts,
return your tray tables
to their locked
and upright positions...
[laughs]
...and prepare for landing.
Hey, Hangman, you look good.
I am good, Rooster.
I'm very good.
I'll see you back on deck.
[breathing heavily]
Maverick is downwind.
No front landing gear.
No tailhook.
Pull the cable
and raise the barricade.
Foul deck! Foul deck!
Raise the barricade!
Go!
Please don't tell me
we lost an engine.
All right,
I won't tell you that.
Okay.
[panting]
You good?
Yeah. I'm good.
[cheering]
Chalked yourself
another kill.
That makes two.
Mav has five.
Makes him an ace.
Captain Mitchell!
Sir.
Thank you for saving my life.
It's what my dad
would've done.
Hey, Mav.
Jimmy.
Is, uh--
Is Penny around?
Uh, she took Amelia
on a sailing trip.
Did she say
when she'd be back?
[Jimmy]
You know, she didn't.
Can I get you anything?
Get in there.
["Hold My Hand" playing]
♪ Hold my hand ♪
♪ Everything will be okay ♪
♪ I heard from the heavens
That clouds have been gray ♪
♪ Hold me close ♪
♪ Wrap me in your aching arms ♪
♪ I see that you're hurtin' ♪
♪ Why'd you take so long ♪
♪ To tell me you need me? ♪
♪ I see that you're bleeding ♪
♪ You don't need
To show me again ♪
♪ But if you decide to ♪
♪ I'll ride in this life
With you ♪
♪ I won't let go till the end ♪
♪ So cry tonight ♪
♪ But don't you
Let go of my hand ♪
♪ You can cry every last tear ♪
♪ I won't leave
Till I understand ♪
♪ Promise me
Just hold my hand ♪
♪ Hold my hand, hold my ♪
♪ Hold my hand, hold my hand ♪
♪ I'll be right here
Hold my hand ♪
♪ Hold my hand, hold my ♪
♪ Hold my hand, hold my hand ♪
♪ I'll be right here
Hold my hand ♪
♪ Hold my hand ♪
♪ My hand ♪
♪ Hold my hand, hold my hand ♪
♪ I heard from the heavens ♪