The woods of Pandora
they hide many dangers.
But the most dangerous thing about Pandora is...
that you may love her too much.
We sing songs to remember.
Each bead, a story in our life.
Pearl for the birth of our son.
I don't care!
- I don't care!
Pearl when we adopted
our daughter, Kiri.
Born by Grace's avatar.
The daughter whose conception is
was a complete mystery.
Pearl for the first union with Eve.
People say, we live in Avey,
and Eva lives in us.
The great mother carries everything
your children in your heart.
Happiness is simple.
But who would have thought it would
a marine like me hack it?
When I met your father,
I tried to kill him.
It was love at first sight.
In an hour, we had four.
When we sent the Heavenly People
back to earth
a few of them remained.
Scientists, loyal to the Na'vi.
And then there was Spider.
He's stuck here.
Too young for a cryo-capsule.
You little beast.
- See you, Norm!
war orphan,
which were raised by people from the laboratory.
Spider, get a spare!
- I'm only going to the village!
He was not part of our family.
He was like a stray cat.
Always there somewhere.
Inseparable from our children.
For Neytiri,
he will always be a stranger.
One of them.
He belongs with his kind.
He's mine!
I took it first.
Why should I leave it to you? -He's mine!
- It took me several years
let my tongue enter my head.
Lo'ak, liar! Give it to me!
- But now that I hear him,
it comes to me like native.
-I hate you!
I hate you endlessly, Lo'ak!
Penisolics!
Enough! Don't let me come there.
He'll come out from behind those big rocks.
There it is.
There. Go get her!
Netejam, the mighty fisherman.
There. Well done.
It's big.
- At the stones.
Where you said.
How tall is he?
- He's this tall. -He's tall!
Time flies.
Like a dream.
Kiri.
-Brother, come on.
Come on.
Smile, you idiot.
Happiness is simple.
Like a night out.
Time without children.
But the problem with luck...
It can disappear in a split second.
A new star in the night.
That can only mean one thing.
Ships. They slow down.
And the Skymen are coming back.
Translated by: Bambula
ONE YEAR LATER
Pulse 168.
Here it is.
You are fine.
Just lie still.
Keep calm.
Yes. Pupillary reaction is good.
Get it out of his face.
Colonel...
can you hear me
Colonel?
You must lie down, sir.
Sedate him!
-Get out of here.
Go Go!
- Call security!
Catch him!
- Catch him!
Hold it!
-Calm down!
Colonel, stop!
Colonel, it's me!
The woods of Pandora
they hide many dangers.
But the most dangerous thing about Pandora is...
that you may love her too much.
We sing songs to remember.
Each bead, a story in our life.
Pearl for the birth of our son.
I don't care!
- I don't care!
Pearl when we adopted
our daughter, Kiri.
Born by Grace's avatar.
The daughter whose conception is
was a complete mystery.
Pearl for the first union with Eve.
People say, we live in Avey,
and Eva lives in us.
The great mother carries everything
your children in your heart.
Happiness is simple.
But who would have thought it would
a marine like me hack it?
When I met your father,
I tried to kill him.
It was love at first sight.
In an hour, we had four.
When we sent the Heavenly People
back to earth
a few of them remained.
Scientists, loyal to the Na'vi.
And then there was Spider.
He's stuck here.
Too young for a cryo-capsule.
You little beast.
- See you, Norm!
war orphan,
which were raised by people from the laboratory.
Spider, get a spare!
- I'm only going to the village!
He was not part of our family.
He was like a stray cat.
Always there somewhere.
Inseparable from our children.
For Neytiri,
he will always be a stranger.
One of them.
He belongs with his kind.
He's mine!
I took it first.
Why should I leave it to you? -He's mine!
- It took me several years
let my tongue enter my head.
Lo'ak, liar! Give it to me!
- But now that I hear him,
it comes to me like native.
-I hate you!
I hate you endlessly, Lo'ak!
Penisolics!
Enough! Don't let me come there.
He'll come out from behind those big rocks.
There it is.
There. Go get her!
Netejam, the mighty fisherman.
There. Well done.
It's big.
- At the stones.
Where you said.
How tall is he?
- He's this tall. -He's tall!
Time flies.
Like a dream.
Kiri.
-Brother, come on.
Come on.
Smile, you idiot.
Happiness is simple.
Like a night out.
Time without children.
But the problem with luck...
It can disappear in a split second.
A new star in the night.
That can only mean one thing.
Ships. They slow down.
And the Skymen are coming back.
Translated by: Bambula
ONE YEAR LATER
Pulse 168.
Here it is.
You are fine.
Just lie still.
Keep calm.
Yes. Pupillary reaction is good.
Get it out of his face.
Colonel...
can you hear me
Colonel?
You must lie down, sir.
Sedate him!
-Get out of here.
Go Go!
- Call security!
Catch him!
- Catch him!
Hold it!
-Calm down!
Colonel, stop!
Colonel, it's me!
Corporal Waynfleet!
Lyle?
That's you?
-Yes sir. And Zee Dog.
And Fike...
I'm all right. Let me go.
I'm all right.
Well...
Isn't this horrible?
Get ready. Two minutes until landing
on Pandora. Safe for Delta V.
OK. Umbilical cord removed.
Oxygen saturation 89.
In case you haven't figured it out yet,
you are Colonel Miles Quaritch.
Only younger, taller, bluer...
And not nearly as gorgeous.
I'm going on a mission in two hours
against a Na'vi stronghold.
The heads thought it was smart
to make a copy of this just in case.
And if you're watching this, well...
That means I pulled my paws.
Parker, what should I say now?
Just remind him how this works.
Here is.
You see this?
These are all your memories and personality.
We're going to send this back to Earth
where are you growing in the lab right now.
We're going to transfer this to you, and then...
Do I do this or do you?
- Hurry up.
Anyway, the idea is to switch
awareness of the most experienced operatives...
As Corporal Wainfleet is there,
and your humble narrator,
into recombinant bodies.
You're recombinant now, Colonel,
filled with my memories and charm.
You will not remember my death,
because it hasn't happened yet,
and won't.
That's right.
-You bet.
Whatever happened,
if you are even a little clone of me,
you will crave revenge.
And Jake Sully will be at the top of that list.
Remember, boy...
A Marine cannot be defeated.
They can kill us,
but we will regroup in hell.
Always loyal.
Ground team, move!
Take this! Go!
Here we go. Two minutes, people.
Here we go.
Bro, we gotta get down there.
-By no means! Dad will skin us!
Come on.
Don't be lukewarm.
Lo'ak!
Come back here, you...
We're taking the whole crate! We take frames
for bullets, rocket launchers, stingers.
Brother, let's go. Come on!
- Lo'ak!
Okay, let's go!
Lo'ak!
Move! Take it!
Take this weapon!
Boy, go!
Lo'ak!
You don't even know how to use it.
My dad taught me.
A fighter jet is coming!
Retreat!
Brother, come on!
Lo'ak, where are you?
We don't care!
Easy easy.
Are you OK?
Yes.
-Where's your brother?
There.
-Where is he? Where?
Get out of here! Go!
We don't care!
Oh no.
No no.
God.
Dad?
What are you doing here, boy?
Where was your mind?
I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry, sir.
You're not in Kansas anymore.
Let's go to Pandora.
I know that everyone to themselves
you are asking the same question.
Why so blue?
Because of the sins of our past life,
we are resurrected in form
our enemy.
This gives us their size,
strength, speed.
And with our training...
It's a pretty potent mix.
Did we get the assignment yet?
-You bet.
Our task is to find and kill
the leader of the Na'vi rebels.
The one they call Toruk Makto.
Jake Sully.
-That!
Attack, attack!
You're mine!
Knock! Come on!
I'm definitely faster when I'm blue.
-You idiot. -Not seriously.
And animals respect me more.
They don't see me as a man.
Stop. You are a man?
They're coming!
HIGH CAMP, OMATIKAY STREET
Run, Spider!
The warband is back!
Come on.
-Here we go. Come on.
Mum! - Tuk...
-Mum. - Knock, Knock.
Choir!
You should be scouts.
Notice the enemies,
and report.
From afar!
Does any of this sound familiar?
Come here!
Jesus. I'll give it to you two
geniuses to complete the task,
and you disobey a direct order.
Kiri, can you help grandma
around the wounded? Please?
My brother is wounded. -It's fine.
- Tuk, go with her. Come on. -Dad.
Sir. I take full responsibility.
- Yes, you take over. That's right.
Because you are the older brother.
You have to act accordingly.
MaJake.
Your son is really bleeding.
- Mother, it's okay. I...
Go get it patched.
Come on, willingly.
You realize it's because of you
your brother almost died.
Yes sir.
You are punished.
You are banned from flying for a month.
Take care of the spawn.
For all of them. -Yes sir.
And get that shit off your face.
You want a kiss on the scratch?
- Give him this. -Okay.
I would use yala bark.
- Here, drink. -Really? And who is Tsahik?
You are...
Move.
you are, grandma,
but the bark is better.
It burns less.
A mighty warrior.
What is it?
Netejam and Lo'ak look up to you.
It was hard for them.
I know.
You are very strict with them.
I am their father.
That's my job.
This is not a unit.
This is family.
I thought we were out of them.
Hey buddy.
How's it going? - Spiders.
Your face is mine.
I'm here.
Only for avatars.
Go around!
Sorry.
Yes. Those blue stripes
they don't make you bigger bro.
Yes, I can still beat you up.
What a day.
- Long.
Really hilarious, folks.
But you know what's really horrible?
You can breathe
earth air for hours,
and I can inhale yours
air for ten seconds.
Yes, Monkey, that's really awful.
For you.
Bye, Max.
- Hi, kids.
Bye. What's up, Max?
What's up, Norm?
Hi Mom.
Maybe I'm just going crazy here
but I see actual proof
systematic response
on a global level.
Can not...
I will not use the term "intelligence."
It is...
Perhaps "awareness" is a better word.
2 3 4
It's like she's whole
biosphere Pandora conscious
and capable of such
cognitive reaction.
Shit, I can't say that.
He will crucify me.
I must say...
Who do you think pumped her up?
I'm pretty sure it was Norm.
-100%.
You two don't deserve to live.
-No no. Think about that.
He is the teacher's pet.
He is always with her in the laboratory.
I would kill myself.
I would drink acid.
Bro, you are right. He is on everyone
recording. Brother, look how he's looking at her.
I mean, their two avatars
they were in the forest alone...
Bullshit!
- People.
Sometimes it's not so great
know who your father is.
No preference. I don't even remember him.
No, Spider.
- Mate.
Spiders...
You are not him.
BRIDGEHEAD CITY
Go!
Straight to the terminal.
Don't stop you!
Take off the masks.
Sir, this is the general.
General Ardmore.
I'm glad, Colonel.
I've heard good things,
but a lot has changed
since your last service here.
Take a walk with me.
The new operations center is here.
It just worked.
These editors can
build a building in 6 days.
We have done more in a year
than for the previous 30.
We're not here to run a mine, Colonel.
As a planetary commander
I have a more important mission.
The earth is dying.
Our task is
to subdue this wilderness.
The goal is to make Pandora
a new home for humanity.
But before we can do that,
we must pacify the enemies.
Sali's attacks
they become bolder and more frequent.
His attacks are well planned.
It has good coordination between
of its ground and air troops.
His troops
they attack our remote places.
Mines, pipelines,
cutting our supply chain.
They attacked the maglev two days ago.
Some information about Sally's operative
base? -Yes. Show me the mountains.
It is a cave system
in the Hallelujah Mountains somewhere.
But every time we send ours
troops up there, we are suffering losses.
Our machines dig up the hornet's nest.
After 10 minutes in the enemy
airspace they overwhelm us.
Colonel, we believe yours will
The blue team will be accepted as the home team
and will not cause an immune response.
And how can we test
that hypothesis, general?
In a hard way.
Excellent.
We are entering the hostile
air space. -I understand.
Brother! - Come on, Monkey!
- People, wait for me!
Tuk, keep up.
-OK OK.
Bro, why did you even take her?
She is a real robber. Says,
"I will say. You must not go to the battlefield."
"I'll tell mom if you don't take me."
- Don't tease her.
Come on.
- Crazy!
Are there any corpses up there?
-Brother, look at this. Come on.
Fuck it.
Curry? Kiri.
Kiri... Kiri.
Kiri.
Are you OK?
- I did that again, didn't I?
Yes you are.
Kiri!
- Kiri!
Kiri, we have to go back.
-Okay, come on.
What is that?
We should always be
at home before the eclipse.
It's too big to be human.
- Avatars?
Maybe, but certainly not ours.
What are you doing?
-I'm following the tracks.
Watch your back.
Clean.
Perimeter set up.
QUARITCH
Damn.
There's no way we should be here.
Dad will punish you.
- Can you stop? -For life.
Brother, we need to see this.
Here we go.
Brother, there are yours
dad and my dad fought.
That's your dad's suit.
- Holy to him.
Lyle, see if you can pull it off
some data from that camera.
That miracle is 100% dead.
-Like us.
I have to report this. - No, bro,
we will get into trouble. -Here we go.
Devil dog, this is Eagle Eye, reception.
- Eagle eye, say.
I see some guys.
They look like avatars,
but they wear camouflage gear
and assault rifles. There are 6 of them. Reception.
What is your position? Reception.
We are at the old cabin.
Who is "you"?
Me, Spider, Kiri...
and Tuk.
Son, listen to me very carefully.
Back off immediately. In silence.
Get out of there! Go! Do you hear?
- Yes, sir, we are leaving.
See, I told you.
- Let's go, let's go.
Dad, I know a faster way!
You're going to be in bad trouble.
-Kiri, stop it. - Guys, come on.
It's almost eclipse, come on.
Put it down! Down! Put it down
or I'll shoot you! -Follow me.
Throw it!
- Immediately!
Don't move! Hands up!
- Put it down. - Spiders.
Catch them! -Come here! Come on!
-Get on your knees! Don't resist!
Do not move.
- See if they have weapons. - Kiri!
keep calm...
Shut. Do not move.
What do we have here?
Colonel, watch this.
Four fingers. We have a half-tan.
Shit.
Show me your fingers.
You're his, aren't you?
You are his.
Where is he?
Unfortunately I don't speak English...
with assholes.
Where is your father?
Not!
Really? Do you want to play like this?
Shut!
Kiri! Not! Stop!
Don't touch her!
Don't hurt her, please.
Do not move.
- What's your name, kid?
Spider Socorro.
Miles?
Nobody calls me that.
I'll be damned. I thought
that they sent you back to Earth.
They can't fit babies
into hibernation, motherfucker.
What are we going to do, boss?
Steel Sky, Blue 1, Unit Leader.
Blue 1, Steel Sky, report.
- We are ready for the draw, reception.
Drive us. -The dragonfly goes left...
We're going to draw.
I warn you, we bring a lot
valuable prisoners. -Let us.
Shut! -Don't move, Blue 1, we're coming
to your position. - We will arrive in 10 minutes.
We're counting down.
Have a seat! - Come on, on the ground!
- Legs up! -Down to the ground!
Lyle, give me the sound for this.
Shut. Don't look up!
That's Sully's wife.
- She's an animal.
Surrender, Quarrel.
Sally. -It's over.
- Son of a bitch.
Nothing is over as long as I breathe.
I was hoping you would say that.
No, you stay with the screen. - But, Dad,
I'm a warrior like you. I need to fight.
We don't care.
- I won't repeat it.
Yes sir.
There is nothing after that.
Would you like us to pick up the leftovers?
Blue 1, get ready.
We're coming in 3 minutes.
Watch out, three minutes.
Cover our backs.
Shut!
Contact back!
-Contact in the back!
Lo'ak!
Shit.
You little piece of shit!
- Lo'ak!
Tuk, come on. Here we go!
- Get back here!
Run away!
- Catch them!
Come on!
Take cover!
Is that you, Mrs. Sally?
I recognize your business card.
Why don't you come out, Mrs. Sally?
You and I have some unfinished business.
Demon! I'll kill you how much
whenever I have to!
You and the corporal were
pretty valuable, right?
You've spawned a whole brood of half-wits.
Navi!
Run, run!
You OK? You okay, boy? -Yes. -Okay.
Follow me. Ready? -Yes sir!
Go!
Come on!
Run, run!
-Spread out. After them.
Spiders?
Spiders!
- Kiri. - Spiders.
Come over! Come on.
The spider is down there.
Not.
Madam, we have arrived. 10 minutes in
enemy airspace.
Blue 1, return to the assembly point.
Immediately.
Blue 1, back off.
- Retreat!
Retreat!
Here we go! Move!
Come on, come on.
Kiri! - Spider!
-Come come. -Not. -Come on.
Run, run.
Come on. Here we go.
It's fine. Are you hurt?
- No, I'm fine.
Tuk, are you hurt?
-Dad!
We are safe.
They are all good?
Mum!
- Knock.
It's fine. We are fine.
Thank you, Great Mother.
Thank you.
Where is Spider?
They took him away.
Okay. It's okay, little one.
OK? He's a tough guy.
OK.
He will be fine.
We'll all be fine.
Damn it! Come on!
Let me out of here!
He is a complete savage.
He thinks he's one of them.
This thing. This Quaritch.
Whatever he is... - What's going on?
He can walk in right under Avey's nose.
This is our family, our home.
- It is about our family, our children.
Can not. You can't ask for this.
I can't leave my people.
I will not.
He's chasing us.
He's targeting our family.
You can't ask for this.
Children only know about the forest. This is our home!
He caught our children.
He held a knife to their throats.
My father gave me this bow when he was dying.
He said I was protecting the people.
You are Toruk Makto!
This will protect people. It's corrupt
caught Spider. And that little guy knows everything.
He knows our whole operation
and can bring them right here.
If people hide us,
will die.
Do you understand?
I have nothing. I don't have a plan...
But I can protect this family.
I can do that.
I know one thing.
wherever we go
this family is our fortress.
Where is Jake Sully?
-I do not know!
We know you do.
Just form a picture in your mind.
Is that one of the floating mountains?
Let me out of here! - He resists us.
Give us a minute. -I do not know!
Just form a thought,
and we will see her.
I do not know!
- I don't like this either, like you.
Which clans would hide him?
-I do not know! You will have to kill me!
Watch this. Abnormal activity
all over the frontal lobe.
This will not stop until we
you don't discover something. Where is he?
I don't know, you bastards! OK?
I do not know!
General, allow me
to try a personal approach.
He is not your son.
Calm down, tiger. Calm down.
Are we good?
Kid, you have the heart of a lion. Those bastards
the scientists put a lot of pressure on you.
But you didn't reveal anything to them.
I respect that.
I thought you might want this.
This is Colonel Miles Quaritch.
The deceased.
Killed in action.
I am not that man.
But I have his memories...
enough to know that...
he wasn't always the best father.
But this is not an apology.
I am not your father. Technically,
you and I are nothing to each other.
But I can help you.
I can get you out of here.
I'm not going to ask you to betray Jake Sully.
I know you would never do that. You are loyal.
And I admire loyalty.
Just come with me.
Otherwise, I'll have to send you back
laboratory coats.
This is very heavy on my heart.
Tarsem is wise for his years.
It will be a strong Olo'eiktan.
The leader must die.
How a leader could be born.
Toruk Makto will disappear.
The people will be safe.
Father protects.
That is its purpose.
One life ends.
The second begins.
Knock.
The sea clans are a world unto themselves.
Thousand Islands.
Unknown territory on which
we could disappear without a trace.
Are we there yet?
AVA'ATLU, METKAJINA VILLAGE
Leave it.
Follow me.
Knock.
Behave yourself.
Slowly. Just calm.
See. What is that?
That's supposed to be the tail?
It's too small. How will they swim?
Don't. Roto, Ao'nung.
Bye.
Tonovari was the chief of Metkajin,
The Greben people.
I see you, Tonovari.
- Jakesley.
I knew him as a solid leader.
But Tonovari was not the one
which worried me.
I see you, Ronal.
Tsahik Metkajina.
Why did you come to us, Jakesal?
- We are looking for a groove.
Utura?
- Yes, a haven for my family.
We are the Greben people.
You are the Forest People.
Your skills will be useless here.
We will learn your customs.
Am I right? -Yes.
Their hands are thin.
Mum. - Their tails are weak.
You will be slow in the water.
These kids aren't even real Na'vi.
-Dad.
Yes we are!
They have demonic blood!
See.
I was born of the people of Heaven, and now I am
Na'vi. OK? You can adapt.
We will adapt. OK?
My husband was Toruk Makto.
He led the clans to victory
over the Heavenly People.
You call this a win?
Hiding among strangers?
Looks like you're Ava
turned her back, the Chosen One.
I'm sorry about my wife.
- Don't apologize for me.
She has flown for a long time and is exhausted.
- Jake.
Toruk Makto is a great war leader.
All the Na'vi people know his story.
But we Metkajin... -Dad.
- We are not at war.
We can't let you
to bring your war here.
I'm done with the war. OK?
I just want to protect my family.
Uturu was requested.
Do we have to leave?
- We'll be fine.
Toruk Makto and his
the family will stay with us.
Treat them as our brothers and sisters.
They don't know the sea.
Therefore it will be like
babies who took their first breath.
Teach them our customs, so they don't
suffered the shame of being useless.
What do we say?
-Thank you.
Thank you.
My son, Ao'nung, our daughter, Tsireya,
will show your children what to do.
Father why...
-It was decided.
Come, I will show you our village.
This way.
Knock, let's go.
Up here.
This is for you. Your new home.
Yes, this will do.
This is great.
It's nice, isn't it?
Salijevi, choir.
-You remember? Family meeting.
Kneel down. Come on.
- Kiri.
What is it?
-Okay.
Children, be on your best behavior.
I really mean it.
Learn fast, engage.
Don't cause trouble. Clear?
Yes sir.
I want to go home.
Oh, Tuck.
Tuk, this is our home now.
We will get through this.
We'll get through this if we look out for each other
others. OK? - What does your father always say?
The Salis stick together.
That's right. The Salis stick together.
This time with a bit of fervor.
Yes. - The Sullies stick together.
- The Sullies stick together.
The Salis stick together.
Come on.
Swim with us.
What's wrong with them?
- They are bad divers.
Stop it. They study.
Are you ok?
- You're too fast. Wait for us.
Just breathe.
Breathe.
You are not good divers. Maybe you are
good at swinging through trees but...
Come on bro. - We don't understand the language
fingers, people. We don't know what you are saying.
I will teach you.
- Where is Kiri? - Kiri? - Who? - Kiri.
Where's Kiri?
- Have you seen her?
Get on board, find a seat,
and don't bother.
Here we go! Hurry up.
- Extra.
Stop, dude!
Listen.
The transmitter is built into that mask.
When we get down and you take her off,
I'll call you back in two minutes
and I'll beat you up the old fashioned way.
Clear?
-Yes sir.
We boarded?
- The team has boarded.
Listen up. Jake Sully went into hiding.
Does not matter. wherever it is,
we will find him and his crazy wife.
To do that, we must become Na'vi.
As soon as possible, completely.
That means we have to eat like the Na'vi.
Ride like a Na'vi. Thinking like a Na'vi.
And that starts with speaking the language.
You call that speaking in tongues?
You sound like a three year old!
Okay, smart guy.
You're just from the monkey mascot
became the official translator.
These are ilu. If you want tolive here
you have to ride.
Gently make the connection.
Feel his breath.
Feel his strength.
Hold on here.
Look at his legs.
-Hold on.
How are you, forest boy?
This is a war mustang. It is not easy to learn.
Maybe you should start with ilo.
Not. This one.
Remember, when you dive,
good position. Very important.
I can do this.
That's right, okay.
Peacefully.
Shit.
I love her already.
Take a breath.
And exhale.
Imagine a flickering flame.
You have to slow down your heart rate.
Take a breath.
Breathe from here.
Exhale slowly.
Lo'ak, your heart is beating fast.
-Sorry. -Try to focus.
Okay.
-Take a breath.
And exhale.
Clear your mind.
Learn to breathe.
Come on!
Keep up, losers!
I will do it.
What is it? -Na'vi children younger than me
they do it with their bare hands.
Jake Sully did it the hard way?
-What do you think?
What are we going to do, Colonel?
This will be good.
Okay, let's go ahead.
You and me, cookie.
Did I mention
that you should tie his mouth first?
Thanks a lot, kid!
Go ahead!
Do you see them?
Okay, let's go.
We're leaving. Come on.
Here we go. We're getting out of here.
That! That's right!
That, Colonel!
Go ahead!
Who's next?
The path of water has no beginning and no end.
The sea is around you and in you.
The sea is your home before your birth...
and after your death.
Our hearts beat in the womb of the world.
Our breath burns in the shadows of the deep.
The sea gives and the sea takes.
Water connects all things.
Life and death.
Darkness and light.
I have her! Tsireia!
-You made it!
This allows us to breathe underwater.
What is she doing?
I do not know.
- He's just looking at the sand.
What did you say?
Are you some kind of freak?
He asked if you were a freak.
Not.
Are you sure?
- You're not even a real Na'vi.
Look at those hands.
Look at them.
Tutanj, fishmouth!
Another four-toed freak.
-Look at his little baby tail!
Don't touch me! - Baby's tail! - Leave it
leave us alone! -He is not normal.
Look at his tail.
Baby tail! He is so cute!
You heard what she said.
Leave them alone.
Big brother has come...
Step back. Immediately.
Smart decision.
And in the future, respect my sister.
Here we go.
Bye!
They're all freaks. The whole family.
Lo'ak.
- I can do this, bro.
I know this hand is weird.
Look, I'm a freak. Foreigner.
But she can do something really cool.
Watch. First, I squeeze her hard like this.
OK? Then...
That's called a blow, cunt!
Don't touch my sister again.
That! Ao'nung!
Show him!
Come here!
Stop it!
It's very stupid!
My tail!
My ear! Let go!
He grabbed my ear!
What's the only thing I asked for? Only!
- Let's stay out of trouble.
To stay out of trouble. Yes.
-It's my fault.
I would not say. You have to stop
you take the blame for this idiot.
Look, dad. Ao'nung bullied Kiri.
He called her a freak.
Go apologize to Ao'nung. -What?
- He is the chief's son. Do you understand?
I don't care how you do it.
Just go make up. Go.
What do the others look like?
-Up.
That's good.
-Much worse.
Get out of here.
What's up with you?
Nothing. I'm all right.
Why shouldn't I be fine?
Why can't I be like everyone else?
Kiri...
What is the forest boy doing here?
Sorry for hitting you.
So many times.
We should be friends.
Come hunt with us. Off the reef.
Where men hunt.
By no means. I'm not allowed.
- I must be asking the wrong brother.
Let's do it.
Come on!
Keep up, forest boy!
THE ROCKS OF THE THREE BROTHERS
You survived!
- That was crazy, bro!
Over here. I know a good place.
Call the fish.
What a moron!
The boys!
Ao'nung!
Come on, this isn't funny!
Congratulations to him.
You are a tulkun.
You saved my life. Thank you.
Thank you.
Dude, I have no idea what you just said.
They hurt you, didn't they?
I'll try to get this out.
Just trust me, okay?
Friends?
That's right, we're friends.
Friends.
Brother!
I'm sorry.
What is it, baby?
Do you miss Spider?
Yes.
-Yes?
But that's not the point.
Okay. What's the matter?
I feel her, Dad.
Who do you feel?
- Eve.
I can hear her breathing.
I can hear her heartbeat.
She is very close.
She is here...
like a word on the tip of the tongue.
I know you think I'm crazy.
You're not crazy, little one.
What does Avey's heartbeat sound like?
Powerful.
Tell him what you told me!
Do you like to look at the stars?
My dad came from a star.
Oh no. Right there.
Lo'ak!
- Oh, man. I'm in trouble.
Go. I'll see you again.
The boy is back!
- That's Sally's son.
They found a boyfriend.
- They found him.
To see you. Okay.
Good. Yes.
Just a few scratches.
I pray that I find strength
not to gouge out the eyes of my youngest son!
Not. My son knew
that he should not lead him outside the reef.
He is guilty.
Okay. Here we go.
Not. Ao'nung is not to blame.
It was my idea.
Ao'nung tried
to talk me out of it.
Really.
-Come on.
Lo'ak.
-I'm sorry.
Come on.
I will take care of this.
Is it true?
- Ao'nung. Where was your mind?
Dad, you said yes
I make friends with those kids.
I was just trying to...
- I don't want to listen.
Dad...
- You disgraced this family.
can i go now
-Next time, I'll tie your tail in a knot.
Do you hear?
-Yes sir. Loud and clear.
Where were you? -Yes. What happened
with that "keep an eye on your brother" thing?
Excuse me, sir.
Why did you take my guilt upon yourself?
Because I know what it's like to be
one big disappointment.
I wish I was there.
The ocean has blessed you with a gift, brother.
The Tulkunis haven't returned yet. After all,
no tulkun is ever alone.
This one was.
One of his fins was missing.
He had a stump. On the left side.
Poor tulkun.
A spider.
-What?
Who is Pajakan?
- A young male who broke away.
He is an exile.
Alone. And his fins are missing.
They say he's a murderer. -No no.
- He killed the Na'vi and other tulkuns.
Not here, but far to the south.
- No, he's not a murderer.
Lo'ak. You're lucky to be alive.
- I'm telling you, people. He saved my life.
He is my friend.
-My little brother!
A mighty warrior faced
with a tulkun murderer and survived.
You're not listening, people.
Lo'ak, I'm listening.
- Lo'ak, come back. -Idiots.
Spiders!
I am glad to see you.
Why are you an exile?
What happened?
It's too painful.
I trust you.
You can trust me.
Bro, that's disgusting.
Go faster!
Here we are.
This is the Cove of the Ancestors.
Our most sacred place.
The eclipse is the best time of day
to be here.
Here it is. This is the Tree of Souls.
My beautiful daughter.
Hi, Mom.
I am very happy to see you.
But you look upset.
My sweet little girl.
It'll be fine.
What is it, honey?
- Why am I different?
What does the Great Mother want from me?
Who was my father?
My soul.
Not!
Come on!
- Kiri!
Kiri!
What is wrong? What is it?
- She had a seizure.
Is he breathing?
Take her to the village! Hurry up!
-Here we go! Let's move! - Knock, come on.
Hello!
-I am glad to see you.
Let's get the equipment. We don't care!
Netejame, keep them away.
How is she?
- He is still unconscious.
No bleeding.
There are no fractures.
No signs of hypoxia.
The brain looks good.
But we have interictal activity
here in the frontal lobe.
Okay. - She must have had a seizure.
We can shed toxins. - So what is it?
I see I'm not needed here.
- You are Tsahik!
Put those things away. -Outside!
You have done nothing!
Come on. We will take a break. -Just a little.
I have to turn off her IV.
Tuktirei.
She said she could feel Ava.
He can hear her heartbeat.
That's it. -What? - It's a classic
frontal lobe epilepsy.
Epilepsy?
-Yes. You see visions.
You enter into states of religious ecstasy
such as those she describes.
Connecting with the Treesoul
is a kind of trigger.
You can't let her do that again.
What? Never?
Jake. If he has another attack
underwater, it could kill her.
Kiri. You're awake!
Oh, Kiri.
Kiri, my sweet child.
My sweet little girl.
Okay, this, "I see you."
That's what I said, didn't I?
Not "Naati. Ngaati."
Okay. It's like it's coming out of your nose.
Chief, long range patrol
she picked up something on the radar.
Rogue fighter aircraft.
Where? - Eastern Sea.
400 km north.
Hold on.
The signal was intermittent, and we lost it
are in the open sea but...
If we continue the trail,
this group of islands is reached.
There are hundreds of islands. That's a big one
search space with many islands.
That's our guy. Give me the ships
aircraft, and I'll bring you his scalp.
Flyers are coming.
- Captain.
Stop everything. - Stop everything.
- Stop everything. I understand.
Bye.
- Are you Scoresby?
You're an asshole requisitioning my ship?
That would be me.
The target is practically this entire archipelago.
I've never been there.
You know the waters, Doc. Who lives there?
Bullets, mostly.
Something Ta'unui. Maybe 50 villages.
And who are you?
I'm Ian Garvin. Marine biologist.
Fifty villages. A hundred villages. Does not matter.
We will search them all.
I hunt tulkuns.
I am equipped for that.
That's what my boys do.
I need to meet the standards.
I'll be good for once.
Then I won't.
If you can't snap out of it,
then get into it!
All crews to their positions!
-Dont touch!
Helmsman, pick him up. Airplane speed.
- Airplane speed, I understand.
What was that?
-What happens?
Tulkoons are back! people,
our brothers and sisters are back.
In its endless cycle
migration, tulkuns came home.
Kiri!
Kiri, come on. Come on!
-Tuk, leave me alone.
Come on!
-What is it?
What do you want?
-Take a look at!
Take a look at.
Come on. Let's go meet them.
See...
That's my spiritual sister.
Sister, I see you.
I see you, sister. I'm happy.
Your son is beautiful.
Thank you. how is your baby
My baby is strong.
I met a guy.
It was a time for stories.
About the time they spent apart.
About death and births.
About old friends and new loves.
THE VILLAGE OF TA'UNUI
Children.
Be still, my people.
We are looking for weapons, communication equipment.
Any technical devices.
Down! And you!
Do you see this?
Stay down and shut up!
This man...
We know it's on these islands.
Here? In this village?
We are a completely separate clan.
That man in the reflection is from the forest.
What does he say?
- They never saw him.
This is the Sea People.
Forest folk don't come here.
I don't believe in that.
He has to get out of here
and went into the forest to find that man.
They don't know anything.
Shoot that animal.
What the hell are you doing?
Calm down.
Are your ears working now? -Calm down!
- Do you see what this can do?
Jake Sully. Toruk Makto!
He told you he didn't know!
Put her down!
-Down!
Down!
Stop it! Stop it!
Make it clear to him.
If you don't hand Sali, we will kill Tsahik.
No, I won't do that.
-Is that so? - I don't want to be a part of this.
Down! - These people don't know anything!
They don't know anything!
Don't move!
Stay down!
Shut!
Are we really going to rock it?
Please. Please don't do that.
That's wrong.
What you are doing here is wrong.
Please.
Burn the huts.
- Set them on fire.
Burn them. All!
- Flamethrowers up.
Burn them!
I'm sorry. I did not know!
-Stop this madness!
I'm sorry.
- Let's get out of here.
Don't touch me!
I'm sorry.
-Here we go.
Get on. OK. Here we go.
What is it?
- Sky people.
They're looking for you, Jakesal. On the south.
It is human with them
Na'vi speaking boy.
Did they kill someone?
-They still have not.
Threaten. But the villagers won't tell them where you are.
According to my order.
We have to find that demon.
Catch him. Kill him.
We have to be smart.
If we attack Quaritch, they'll know where we are,
and they will come here with everything they have.
So what is our plan?
It's Toruk Makto! - Head down.
- Was he here?
There is no point in this.
- No, they are dragging us.
If we press harder, he will continue
to run away. We have to get him out into the open.
I'm done with this.
I need to meet the standards.
Do you want to hunt?
We are hunting.
Here? Not here.
There are too many villages.
Not. No no.
Sincerely, sir...
You don't understand the close connections between
tulkun and oceanic Na'vi.
That would be like im
you kill a family member.
If we start hunting here,
the enemies will attack us.
Exactly.
One enemy in particular.
I know how you feel.
I feel all alone too.
Tell me. Why are you an exile?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
It's fine.
You allowed this.
You let him bond with an exile!
Tsireia. You disappoint me, daughter.
And you, son of a great warrior,
they didn't teach you that way.
The spider saved my life, sir.
You don't know him. - No, Lo'ak.
Have a seat.
Sit down!
Hear my words, boy.
In the days of the First Songs,
tulkuns fought among themselves,
for territory and for revenge.
But they realized that killing,
no matter how justified,
it only leads to more killing.
So killing is forbidden.
Such is the custom of tulkuns.
A spider is a killer,
that's why he's an exile.
I'm sorry, sir. But you are wrong.
- Lo'ak. You are talking to Olo'ejktan.
I know what...
-Enough!
I know what I know.
Enough.
I'll take care of him.
This storm will pass.
Lo'ak, I saw something today.
I saw sh
a smart guy
who was chosen by the tulkun.
I am very proud of you.
The spider didn't kill those guys.
I saw it all.
The demon ship killed the mother exactly
in front of him. He gathered the young males
and reef boys to attack the ship.
And they killed them all...
Heavenly people. Not him.
He is not a murderer. - No, Lo'ak.
According to the tulkun custom, it is.
He is responsible for those deaths.
Does it have to work out
because of that the rest of your life?
He knows that what he did was
wrong. He would never do it again.
We have to tell my father...
Not. I already have enough
problems with his father.
Your father will understand this.
- No, it won't. He doesn't understand anything.
The whole clan hates me. Demon blood.
Foreigner. They just see it.
I see you.
You are the tulkun's brother.
You are one of us now.
Did you find your mother? -Mother and cub.
Strong signal. Distance, 4,000.
Insert it into the hull of the ship.
- I'm hanging up, I understand.
Underwater teams, two minutes!
Get in there!
The door is closed!
Come on, faster! Faster!
Crews in their ships.
Two minutes. Let's make some money.
Ship crews! let's
let's release the ropes! Release the ropes!
All ships in the water!
Ships in the water!
Let's go, babe!
Here we go!
Prepare the depth charges
and fire, fire, fire!
What is that?
What are they doing?
These are echolocation sensors.
That's how they manage.
They have to keep them above the surface of the water,
or they will go deaf.
Picadores! Get in there!
Come on. Get in there. Get in there!
It will isolate the female from the rest of the flock
using a sound cannon.
They target the mother because the cub swims slowly,
and she won't leave him.
Do they sometimes resist?
- No, they never raised their fins.
Although they are hard to kill.
Underwater teams, move!
And let go.
Release, release.
Here's our girl. Target in sight.
3-6 ready with harpoons.
Let's go, kid.
We enter from below,
where their armor has holes.
Okay, let's go. Get in there.
- I'm coming in. Bring me closer.
Hold her steady.
In range. Activate one.
I activate, target engaged.
And one fired.
Another one ready.
Activate one.
- I'm activating. -Fire away.
Good shot. Activate another.
- I'm activating. Another shot.
To the balls!
-Fine.
3-6, you owe us a beer.
See, the balloons slow her down,
and keep it afloat. -Yes.
On her. Take me there.
Right on her. 30 meters.
A harpoon with an explosive tip.
Ten meters. Take me there.
Put me in your pocket.
Now calm, calm.
Wait. Wait.
Go tighter!
Watch your ponytail, Colonel!
Full power back!
-Back to maximum, I understand.
Hold her.
She received an explosive harpoon in her chest
but he still runs away. Wonderful.
The only way to get to the gland is
from below. We drill through the hard palate
in the brain. And...
These are very intelligent beings.
Probably smarter than us.
They are not smarter than me.
- You set the criteria very low.
I'm the one with the harpoon.
Yes.
How do you know? That they are smarter than us?
-More neurons, more connections.
Not only are they smarter,
they are deeply sensitive.
More spiritual.
This area fits here
our emotional centers,
but proportionally it is much larger.
They have music, philosophy, mathematics...
A complex language.
Okay. We begin.
- Show me the money.
What is all this for?
-That's right. Amrita.
Unfortunately for the monstrous,
this miracle stops aging in humans.
It stops him completely.
Gram by gram, the most valuable
substance known to man.
This tube is worth about 80 million.
Think fast!
Please do not.
It's never funny.
Amrita finances everything
here on pandora now.
Even your research.
Right, Dr. G? - That's why I drink.
You just take it?
Throw away the rest?
Deflate the balloons.
Let's sink her!
Not. Leave the balloons.
I want them to know it was us.
I charge extra
when they use me as bait.
Her name is Ro'a.
She was my spiritual sister.
She composed songs.
Very respected.
We would sing together.
She waited many cycles
mating to get this cub.
The clan was very happy for her.
What is this, Tonovari?
What is this?
My spiritual sister and hers
the baby was killed by the Skymen.
This war has come to us.
We knew that our people were being hunted by tulkunas.
But that was over the horizon,
far. Now it's here!
You have to understand
how Heavenly people think.
They are not interested in the Great Balance.
- We do not answer to the Heavenly People!
Listen up. Listen to him.
The people of heaven will not stop.
This is just the beginning.
Tell the tulkuns to leave.
Tell them to go away.
Shall they go?
You live among us and you haven't learned anything.
We will fight to protect
our brothers and sisters!
No no.
If you attack, if you fight,
then they will destroy you.
It will destroy everything you love.
Not!
- Hear my words! Hear my words!
Calm down. Calm down!
Listen to my father. -Damn!
- He is telling the truth.
Tell the tulkuns,
if they get hit by one of these,
they are marked for death.
And call me, I'll shut him up.
Saving their lives,
that's all that matters. Is not it?
Saving your family.
Tell the tulkuns.
Go away. Go!
We have to fight.
MaJake. I will not stand
and to do nothing.
It's a trap. They want us to fight back.
They don't hunt tulkuns. They are hunting us.
You're not going anywhere, little brother.
- I have to warn Pajakan about the transmitters.
Not. Your idiotic
the ass must stay here.
He is an exile. There is no one
other than me to warn him.
Bro, why do you always have to do so much
to aggravate the situation?
Not. You think why can't I be perfect
son like you? The perfect little soldier.
Well, I'm not you! OK?
I'm not you.
He's my brother. I'm going.
He is your brother?
No, I'm your brother.
Lo'ak!
Let me.
Lo'ak! -Come back!
-Come on. He goes to Pajakan.
Come back!
Here comes Lo'ak! Lo'ak!
- Lo'ak!
Lo'ak goes to find Pajakan!
-Wait!
Hold on.
All crews in positions.
Advertise a general call. - All right, people.
Come on. Let's make some money!
Brother!
Lo'ak!
- Stop!
What is it? What is wrong?
Shit!
Stay calm.
I will solve this.
Shit!
Lo'ak!
Brother, come on!
-Help me!
Hurry up, the ship is coming! There they are!
Brother, come on!
Come on bro.
-Hurry up!
Report this! Call dad!
Call dad! Come on! Do it!
Just do it. - Dad, I mean,
Devil's dog. Can you hear me?
Did you see where they went?
- This is Eagle Eye, do you hear?
They went beyond the reef.
- Yes, Lo'ak. -Dad!
We are with the tulkun who is being attacked.
The killer ship arrives.
It is about 2 km away. - Who is with you?
All of us. Ao'nung and Tsireja too.
We are at Stena Three Brothers.
take cover,
and do not engage in combat. OK?
Can you hear me?
Do not engage in combat. On our way.
Yes sir. -Is approaching!
- Three, two, pull! - Pull!
Children are under attack!
Children were attacked.
Tulkun dams. And your children too.
A demon ship?
-Yes! We have to go!
Weapon.
Sound the alarm!
You better stay.
- I will ride! Come on!
Underwater teams, close the hatch.
In two minutes!
Ao'nung!
Hurry up! Come on! Brother, hurry!
Quick, quick!
Drag! Now!
All of! Together!
- Pull!
I'll be damned.
Sally's children.
Here we go. You do not.
- Get on!
Distance 700 meters.
The transmitter signal is good.
Pull harder!
- Pull!
-Come on!
He was taken out!
Kiri, it's taken out! -Go. Tuk, go.
Come on. Get out of here!
Go there! I'll get them out of here.
Okay.
- Lo'ak, come on.
Spiders! Come on, dive in!
Dive in!
- Knock, get a hold of yourself.
Distance 300 meters.
-Ready the depth charges
and fire, fire, fire.
No depth charges. Scoresby, are you listening?
These children are worthless dead to me.
Don't shoot.
Surround. Make a cordon around them.
Drop the submarines into the water.
Underwater teams, get excited.
Crabs go to the right.
Surround them.
Don't lose them. Follow them.
- Wings up! We're going in!
Extra!
Target captured.
Two fired.
Where is Tuck?
Have you seen her?
Knock!
Target in sight.
It's coming!
-We have to go!
Go online.
- I'm transferring. -Fire away.
Hold on!
- Let me out!
Watch out! - Knock, move!
- Move your hand!
Cut her!
-Hurry up!
Kid, come back here!
Put down the weapon. - Throw the weapon down!
- Put him down. -Put him down!
Stay down.
Catch him!
Put the weapon down!
Throw it away, now! Put him down!
- Drop the knife. Throw it.
What are you doing? Stop it!
Stop it. Don't hurt them.
Beforestop moving.
- Spider!
Brother, are you okay?
-Yes. Awesome, bro. Never better.
Stop. Lie still.
-Shut!
Return to the bridge.
Hold it there!
I'm going, I'm going.
Yes. I remember you.
Tie them to the fence. All of them.
Here we go! -Here we go. Move!
- Over here.
Watch out for them. They bite.
-Kneel down. Get on your knees.
Give me your hand.
-Not!
Now the second one.
-Not.
Be brave.
The Na'vi are coming!
Spread yourself out. Weapons up.
-Dad! - Drive left. Spread yourself out.
Stop. Stop them.
It's Sally.
300 meters.
They have our children.
Your daughter. Knock. Lo'ak.
Jake, tell yours
friends to step down.
If you want your children back,
come alone
You know it's not smart to test
my resolve.
Lo'ak! Not.
I took you under my wing, Jake.
You betrayed me.
You were killing your fellow man.
Good men. Good women.
I will not hesitate to kill your children.
Wait a minute.
Stay here.
They are tulkun killers.
They must die. Here. Today.
They want me.
That's what this is all about, okay?
Hunting for our tulkuns.
The kidnapping of our children.
You put this on our necks!
You!
Then I have to do this.
Offer expires soon.
What have you decided?
Don't shoot. I am coming.
MaJake, what's going on?
MaJake?
Be on the lookout, folks.
All weapons.
Easy hit.
- If you hit him now, they will attack.
Wait until he's on board.
Spider!
Shoot. Shoot!
Brother!
Turn!
- I'm turning! - Turn me around!
Put me in position to shoot!
Come on, come on!
Turn me around! Quick, quick!
Get in there so I can be in range.
Quick, quick.
Down!
Damn!
Shoot! Shoot!
Sally approaches. Keep an eye on him.
- Okay, let's go.
Get on. We're taking off.
Someone guess something!
Stop!
After them! Come on!
Breakthrough! Put on your masks!
Put on your masks! Come on!
Get him out of here!
-Come on!
Calm down!
Faster, faster!
Damage report!
-The flood! Sections two and three.
Are you OK?
To the left of the bow!
- Sharp left!
Shoot!
Put me in position to shoot!
I got you!
Untie us!
- He doesn't react!
Get us off the hook!
- Who has the harpoon now?
Backwards with maximum power!
Recharge!
No cable, idiot!
We can't sail anymore.
Water seeps in. Pumps on.
- To weapons!
I thought it was you
intelligent species here, Scoresby.
Shut up, Garvin.
Where are you?
Insolent rascal.
You think you're very smart, don't you?
Bend down!
The pumps are not working.
- Abandon the ship!
Abandon ship! Get him on the boat.
-Yes sir!
Let's go, narowhat! Move! Put on your masks!
We don't care! - Hello, kid
brother. Do you need help?
Shut. Come on.
Set us free.
Get Tuk out of here.
- Brother, hurry!
Who is the mighty warrior? Come on. Say.
- Brother! -Come on. Here we go.
Lo'ak!
- They have Spider.
We have to save him. Come on.
Come on bro.
We can't leave him.
Let me!
Not!
See!
Let's go, baby. Get up.
- I'm not your soul, pervert!
We have to go back for her.
- Knock, stop!
The Salis stick together.
Hang in there, folks. Wait.
OK. You can board!
Check the mask. Check if it is
popular. -I'm fine, dumbass.
Hurry up! This is an evacuation, folks.
Here we go!
Tuk, this is not a good idea.
Knock!
Cut here.
Not!
I have her.
We can still do this.
-You bet.
I can't believe I'm tied up again.
Hurry up guys.
Brother, come on.
-Here we go.
Thanks guys.
Here we go! -Not!
-Brother, come on! - Quick, quick!
Run, run!
Give me that.
Go, go!
- This way.
Take cover!
Do you see them?
Brother! That was crazy, bro.
Climb up!
- Come on, bro.
You idiot. I am affected.
Shit! Help me!
Hold it up!
- I'm holding him.
Come on.
Catch him.
- Bro, I got it.
Curse.
- Straighten him up!
Brother, come on.
It's okay bro. I'm holding you.
-Hurry up! Come on, come on!
They have Kiri and Tuk.
I can't go back.
Dad! Dad, help!
It's Netejam!
Hurry up!
-Here is! Take it.
Oh no.
- Netejam is injured!
Jake. -Come on. Come on.
-Hurry up, please!
Drag!
Brother, watch his head.
Come on!
Just watch his head.
Okay.
It's okay bro. We will help you.
-Oh no.
Press. Press it.
Dad, I...
-It's fine. I'm here.
No no.
It's okay, son.
I'm here.
I want to go home.
I know. It's okay, let's go home.
Go home.
It's fine.
- Dad, I...
We don't...
Not. No no.
We don't care!
Great mother. No, Great Mother.
Please.
Oh, my son. My son.
Not!
My son!
Can you hear me, Corporal?
Yes, I think you hear me.
I have your daughters.
Same offer as before.
You for them.
Not!
Where are your sisters?
Your sisters. Where are they?
I do not know. -Where are they?
- They are tied up on the ship.
They are by the moon pool.
At the shaft through the deck. In the middle of the ship.
What?
-Come on. I will show you.
Come on. I will show you.
- Call me, corporal. -Come on.
Zee, up at the top. - I need something,
Jake, or there will be consequences.
I hear you.
Here we go. -Here we go!
-Here we go. We have to go. Let's go.
Not! -Here we go.
Listen. Listen to me.
Listen to me.
They hold our daughters.
I need you to be with me.
And you have to be strong.
Now. With a strong heart.
With a strong heart.
Let's go get our daughters.
You stay with your brother.
- Dad, I want to go with you.
You've done enough.
-Dad...
Don't shoot.
Here we go.
He is coming.
I caught myself. Come on, come on!
Let's take care of this guy.
That's why we came here.
Stay with him.
-Not...
Be careful guys.
Come on.
Where are they? - Middle deck.
Where they launch submarines.
There is a pool in the middle.
They are by the bow rail.
No no. Stay there.
Come on in, Corporal. This ship is sinking
and your girls with him.
Your son didn't have to die.
It's your fault.
You thought you could protect the family,
but you can't.
Only in one way
you can protect them.
Let's get this over with
before you lose another child.
Lay down!
Who is affected?
- Zdinarsik, do you hear? -I'm here!
Clean!
Preigers. Do you hear?
Look up. Look up!
Forward!
Force left. Go!
Force right. Go around her.
Does anyone see anything?
MaJake!
It's mom!
That's right.
They're coming for you.
Dad! Dad.
Where is your sister?
Where is she? -There.
Okay, stay behind me.
Kiri!
Time is running out, Corporal.
You already lost one child today.
Do you really want to lose another one?
Don't challenge me!
Just kill him, dad!
Kiri!
Weapons down. -Do not.
Do not do that. -Down!
Kick them away.
Do it!
Not.
Put the handcuffs on. -Not! Do not
to hurt her, okay?
Stop there! -Do not!
-Do not move! Not a step.
Put the handcuffs on. Immediately.
-Bastard!
Please don't hurt her.
Let go. Or I cut.
You think I care about some kid?
He is not mine.
We're not even the same species.
Please don't hurt her.
Please let her go.
Do not. -Please!
- Don't kill him.
Listen to me! Let her go.
Don't hurt her.
Mom, don't kill him.
-Son for son.
Please don't hurt her.
I'm cutting. - Please let her go.
OK? Just let her go.
Not!
Kiri... Kiri.
Kiri.
Spiders.
- Spider, get them out of here.
14 12
Come on. Society. Knock.
- I owe you death.
Mum. -Mum.
- Come on. -Come on.
Please. Mum.
You're not going, are you, Jake?
When you know I'm out there somewhere.
When you know I'll never give up.
I'll come get you. And when I come
I will kill your whole family.
Dad...
Let's wrap this up then.
Jake!
It's coming! -Back. Back to the ship! Come on!
-Tuk, swim.
Stay close. - Keep going.
-Stay close. -Come on.
Knock!
Mom, take my hand!
-Hold on!
Mum!
Kiri, come on. -Not...
-Kiri, we have to go. Come on. -Not!
Come on! Climb up!
Climb up!
Kiri, come on!
Come on let's go!
Mum! -Swim! Swim.
Come on, Tuck. Climb up!
Mum...
-Come on!
Go, go, go!
Keep climbing!
Come on!
I'm holding you.
Give me your hand! Come on!
Open them!
- Step back. Step back.
Come on.
Knock!
Climb up! Come on!
Go up!
We're rolling! Go Go!
-Okay...
Not!
-Mum!
Kiri! Move on!
Over here!
-Okay.
Come on!
Open them!
Mum!
Come on!
Go, Tuck!
There is no way out!
Let's stay together, okay?
-Yes. - Let's stay together. -Yes.
Great mother.
Great mother, help us!
Kiri!
Brother!
- Mom and Dad are down there. In the ship.
Get a hold of yourself.
- Brother, I caught myself. Come on!
Okay.
Jake!
Dad.
Fuck!
Come on son of a bitch!
Dad, breathe.
- I don't care?
No, Dad.
I am Lo'ak.
Oh, Lo'ak.
- I'm sorry, sir.
I feel sorry for Netejam. It's my fault.
- Just focus.
Focus on this now.
We're losing the air pocket.
Come on. We have to go. Come on, Dad.
Do you know how to get out? -I think I know.
But, Dad, he's going to have to hold his breath for a long time.
I can't stand it.
You can. You must leave now. -Not.
I can't lose you either, Dad.
Please.
Mom, I'm scared.
Everything is fine.
Stay close to me. Stay close to mom.
It's fine.
You just have to slow down your heart rate.
Be very calm.
Breathe from here.
The path of water has no beginning and no end.
The sea is around you and in you.
The sea is your home before your birth
and after your death.
The sea gives
and the sea takes
Water connects all things.
Life and death.
Darkness and light.
Bye.
- Kiri. - Kiri.
Everything's gonna be alright, sis.
Mom, I'll give you this.
That will help you.
Dad, you can do this.
Trust me. Calm your heart.
Take a deep breath.
Last breath.
Follow me.
Hold on. Just breathe.
Just breathe.
Thank you.
I see you, son.
MaJake!
Dad! -Mum!
-Dad. Dad.
Come on. Come here.
Knock! -I got you.
-Here is.
Brother.
The Salis stick together.
That was our biggest weakness
and our great strength.
Thank you, Great Mother.
Thank you.
Here we go.
Son...
Come with me.
Spiders!
Monkey!
Spiders.
Are you OK?
-Yes.
Come here.
Son for son.
Every songbook must
to have the last bead.
Father protects. That is its purpose.
People say it's all energy
just borrowed.
And that one day you have to bring her back.
Eva carries all her children in her heart.
Nothing is ever lost.
I don't care!
- I don't care!
My family and me
we leave tomorrow
Far away from here.
Your son rests with our ancestors.
You are Metkajina now.
And so it happened.
We are the Sea People now.
This is our home.
Dad! Look what I caught!
It's big.
She was there in that pool.
At the stones. Where you said.
What's up, dad?
Why are you crying?
I'm just happy to see you, boy.
I'm happy to see you too.
Here is. You try it.
Okay.
Did you leave any for me?
-Maybe.
Look at that. You see?
I see now.
I can't save my family by running away.
This is our home.
This is our fortress.
We will resist here.
Translated by: KimSour
AVATAR: THE WAY OF WATER